<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Video Blog with Mark Ramey</title>
    <description>Our mission at The Mark Ramey Group is to be your best resource for real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The The Mark Ramey Group, your professional Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 09:08:08 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 09:08:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Comparing the Positive Aspects of Buying &amp; Renting</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_GfxT5--87s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Which is better right now: buying or renting?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the state of our market and economy lately, many people have been reaching out to ask me the following question: Is it better to buy or rent?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Homeownership allows you to personalize your home and make choices when it comes to decorating and remodeling.%20http://localhost:4000/comparing-the-positive-aspects-of-buying-renting.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Homeownership allows you to personalize your home and make choices when it comes to decorating and remodeling.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the positives of renting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;There’s no down payment.&lt;/b&gt; You simply have to come up with your first month’s rent and a security deposit, which can be less expensive than a down payment on a home.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;You’re not responsible for maintenance&lt;/b&gt;—the landlord takes care of it all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;It’s a short-term obligation.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;It gives you freedom&lt;/b&gt; to decide where you want to live on shorter notice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, here are some of the pros of buying a home:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rental rates are at an all-time high.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mortgages are &lt;i&gt;less than&lt;/i&gt; rent.&lt;/b&gt; After the down payment, mortgage payments are frequently less than rental rates, meaning that people can often get into a nicer property by buying it than they can by renting it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;You can pay your own debt.&lt;/b&gt; Instead of paying down someone else’s mortgage like you do when you rent, you can drop your own debt, which puts you one step closer to financial freedom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;The market appreciates.&lt;/b&gt; On average, properties in our area will appreciate anywhere between 3% and 5% each year. For a $200,000 property, that’s between $6,000 and $10,000 of potential annual appreciation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;It gives you freedom.&lt;/b&gt; Homeownership allows you to personalize your living space and make fun choices when it comes to decorating and remodeling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any more questions about whether it’s in your best interest to rent or purchase, consider me your resource. You can reach out to me via phone or email at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 16:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comparing-the-positive-aspects-of-buying-renting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comparing-the-positive-aspects-of-buying-renting.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do I Get My Kids Excited to Move?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nD6Er8A_heg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Moving is stressful for kids, so help them along with these great tips.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving is often very stressful for children. The first things they think about are giving up their friends and their favorite aspects of their current home. I want to share a few strategies that may make them feel more comfortable with the process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first suggestion is getting them involved in the move from the beginning. &lt;strong&gt;Talk to them about the benefits they’ll receive from moving.&lt;/strong&gt; Maybe it’s an extra room or a larger yard where they’ll have more space to play, or perhaps they’re getting a swimming pool. I’d be thrilled about that too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also involve them in the house hunt. Bring them along as you’re looking for properties, make it a family event; this can be exciting for them. Additionally, you could ask them to help design their new bedroom by picking out a paint color or a new comforter. You should also &lt;strong&gt;spend some time in the new neighborhood&lt;/strong&gt; and try to introduce them to some of the other children in the community so they feel welcomed and connected to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Get children involved in the moving process from the beginning.%20http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-get-my-kids-excited-to-move.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Get children involved in the moving process from the beginning.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also want to take them to their new school. Let them see it, experience a little of it, and get excited about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions about preparing children to move or real estate in general, please feel free to call or email us. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 11:29:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-get-my-kids-excited-to-move.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-get-my-kids-excited-to-move.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Staying Connected</title>
        <description>&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px;&quot;&gt;Most of you know that my sister Christi and I work together at Keller Williams Classic Realty. I am mentioning this because I have been watching how families have been staying connected during the last few months. Wow, the world has changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px;&quot;&gt;The word &lt;em&gt;Zoom&lt;/em&gt; is now an adjective (get on the &lt;em&gt;Zoom&lt;/em&gt; meeting), a noun (everyone sign in for the &lt;em&gt;Zoom&lt;/em&gt;) and a verb (we will be &lt;em&gt;Zooming&lt;/em&gt; in 10 minutes). That has all happened since March and it doesn’t matter if you were born in 1930 or 2018, you all know what those mean! Personally, I have been suffering from &lt;em&gt;Zoom&lt;/em&gt; fatigue (Holy Crap, now it’s a condition) and I am looking forward to a birthday party where I am actually in the room with the cake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px;&quot;&gt;I have to admit though that there are some benefits to this new world we live in. One of them is that most of Christi and my family lives in Illinois and for the first time ever we had an Easter &lt;em&gt;Zoom&lt;/em&gt; get-together with relatives neither of us had seen in years. Luckily the video quality on &lt;em&gt;Zoom&lt;/em&gt; isn’t that good so we all looked just as young as the last time we saw each other. We have also been able to stay in contact with friends, clients and co-workers in a way that allows us to get a glimpse (literally) into their lives and living rooms. In a weird way, the need to stay apart has really made us more creative in finding ways to stay connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px;&quot;&gt;I will take that thought one step further and say that I have also noticed that same creativity has come through as people have adapted to this new world. Face masks that match outfits, people using their eyes to smile, and being able to count on at least 2 out of 10 shoppers at Publix correctly using the directional arrows for the grocery aisles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px;&quot;&gt;Best of all I have realized how lucky I am to have Derek in my life. How great it is to be able to work with my sister every day and how blessed I am to have the best team of people working with me that I could imagine having. I have watched them all adapt to new systems, work environments and challenges that none of us saw coming. We may not be sitting in adjacent desks as much as we use to be but we are there for each other every day. So maybe the world hasn’t actually changed much at all.&amp;nbsp; – Sincerely, Mark Ramey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/mark-zoom---earth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;75%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 14:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/staying-connected.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/staying-connected.html</guid>
        
        <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Hassle-Free Way to Enroll My Kids in OCPS?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hDqZ6-alROU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every parent wants to set their child up for success in school, and here’s how.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving is stressful enough, but getting your kids into that new school district can be a whole challenge unto itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your kids are returning to Orange County Public Schools or some of the surrounding schools that operate similarly, enrollment is made easier by the fact that the &lt;strong&gt;students—especially high schoolers—are allowed to choose their classes the year prior.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge that my husband Eric and I had, however, arose when we hosted two exchange students; Oliver was from the Czech Republic, and Thomas was from Brazil, but both of them arrived just one week before school started. When we went to go pick their classes, they didn’t know what was available to them, so it made the process stressful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you take care of all of these things, your child will be set up for success in our wonderful Orange County schools!%20http://localhost:4000/whats-the-hassle-free-way-to-enroll-my-kids-in-ocps.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you take care of all of these things, your child will be set up for success in our wonderful Orange County schools!”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They also needed a student ID&lt;/strong&gt; to obtain their student device (rather than rely on books, students in Orange County Public Schools operate using a device that gives them easy, centralized access to their teachers, assignments, and grades). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I dropped the ball when it came to registration and having all of the necessary information prepared, Thomas and Oliver had to start their first day of school without a set schedule. &lt;strong&gt;To avoid the same snafu for your kids, remember the following:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get a list of classes in advance so your kids know what’s available. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you register your child in time for them to be issued a student ID number. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having that ID will give them timely access to their student device so they can practice using it before classes start. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure they stay in the habit of keeping their device charged!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take care of all of these things, your child will be set up for success in our wonderful Orange County schools! Hopefully, you found this message helpful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about real estate, or if you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, you can always reach out to me via phone or email. I’m here to be a resource for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 12:59:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-hassle-free-way-to-enroll-my-kids-in-ocps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-the-hassle-free-way-to-enroll-my-kids-in-ocps.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Do People Stage Their Home Before Selling?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RS8uWZNPIrU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Home staging pays for itself because of these three facts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are three reasons why staging your home is a benefit to your home sale:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Buyers will pay more.&lt;/strong&gt; According to a recent survey by Moritz Research, 63% of homebuyers would be willing to pay a higher price for a home that is staged well and in good condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. You can stand out among the competition.&lt;/strong&gt; A properly staged home is particularly important in a market with a lot of inventory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. We can broaden the market.&lt;/strong&gt; When a home is staged, it appeals to more buyers. The more buyers it appeals to, the more showings and offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions for me about these staging tips or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 10:56:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-do-people-stage-their-home-before-selling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-do-people-stage-their-home-before-selling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Know If Renovations Are in Your Best Interest</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/paBpq4WsQAw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The first step in solving the renovation dilemma is knowing your home type.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When making a decision as to whether to make renovations on your home, I’d like you to consider which home you have in the marketplace. Generally, there are three types of homes that are selling in today’s market: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;The first type of home is the brand-new home.&lt;/strong&gt; Perhaps it’s a new build, or it recently underwent a complete overhaul renovation to thoroughly modernize it. This home will appeal to 99% of buyers in our marketplace.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;The second type of home is the one that’s in clean, move-in condition.&lt;/strong&gt; It may need a few renovations to suit individual buyers’ tastes, but the basics are all up to par.&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;The third type of home is the one that needs repair.&lt;/strong&gt; It &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; sell as is, but whoever purchases it does so knowing that it will need some serious work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Simply painting and updating flooring can add anywhere from 10% to 15% to your home’s value.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-know-if-renovations-are-in-your-best-interest.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Simply painting and updating flooring can add anywhere from 10% to 15% to your home’s value.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selling the first home is fairly straightforward: I have my professional photographer come out to snap some stellar pictures, we get it on the market, and we get it sold. These types of homes usually sell quickly with little to no hassle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second type of home is just as desirable as the first in today’s market. Buyers may want to renovate a few areas upon moving in, but theoretically, a buyer could move in and not &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; to do any no serious work. For selling this type of home, I would just make sure that we have fresh coats of paint on the walls, and clean, new carpet or flooring. Also, check your home’s curb appeal; trim the shrubs, get some flowers in the garden, and put down some fresh mulch. Once you tackle these relatively easy improvements, you’ll already be in the best position on the market. Simply painting and updating flooring can add anywhere from 10% to 15% to your home’s value. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the third type of home, you have to anticipate making some hard choices.&lt;/strong&gt; If you choose to do nothing to it, it will likely sell 20% to 30% below what Type 1 and Type 2 homes sell for. So, if you’re the owner of Type 3 and need to make some renovations, we have some amazing, fully vetted professionals that we’d love to connect you with. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any specific questions on this topic, or if you’d like me to show you what your home would likely go for on the market before and after certain renovations, please reach out to me by phone or email. I’m here to be a resource for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 15:12:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-know-if-renovations-are-in-your-best-interest.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-know-if-renovations-are-in-your-best-interest.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Delicious Omelettes</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0rem 100px;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-5&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://d1qmdf3vop2l07.cloudfront.net/modest-salamander.cloudvent.net/compressed/_min_/1abf592ba2ad2c3245498a13583795c7.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:90%;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-7&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px; margin-right: 40px;&quot;&gt;So, with the current state of the world I thought a nice sort of funny letter would be appropriate. During the weekends this last school year we would sometimes have one of the other exchange students come over and spend the weekend with Oliver and Thomas. One of their best friends from the exchange program was a young man named Andri from Switzerland. Needless to say, with all of these students in the house the warning sign to the left was appropriate. Derek would even say necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px; margin-right: 40px&quot;&gt;Andri was not the kind of young man who watched idly from the sidelines. He was always getting involved with everything going on around him.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row row-no-gutters&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0rem 100px;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-5&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://d1qmdf3vop2l07.cloudfront.net/modest-salamander.cloudvent.net/compressed/_min_/5fb4f7738558ad7aa811201987436f84.jpg&quot; style=&quot;width:110%;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-7&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px; margin-right: 40px; margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;I couldn’t even make breakfast for him. As soon as I started making omelettes one morning, he was right there asking how I made them. I showed him how and he made them for all of us that morning and any other morning that he was at the house.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px; margin-right: 40px; margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;Andri wrote the thank you letter to the left on the back of the above warning sign. His host mother brought it over after he had flown back to Switzerland while he still could.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px; margin-right: 40px; margin-left: 40px;&quot;&gt;I don’t think any of us were expecting the students' exchanges to end so quickly but all three boys are back home safely with their families. I actually had to drive Thomas to Miami to get him on what seemed to be the last flight on the planet going to Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-indent: 40px; margin: 0rem 100px; margin-right: 140px;&quot;&gt;You might be wondering how to make delicious omelettes. It just takes practice until you can flip the eggs. Once you have that figured out, I suggest teaching it to someone else. You never know what can make a lasting memory. – Mark Ramey&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 13:19:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-delicious-omelettes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-delicious-omelettes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Do You Need to Get a Home Loan Today?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jVv7pFFPZZQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;A pre-approval will give you a leg up as a homebuyer. Here is what you’ll need to get one.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often I hear buyers ask, “What do I need to bring to my lender so that I can make an application for a loan?” Here’s your checklist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, you’ll need at least three months’ worth of bank statements.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll also need proof of down payment, which will come from those bank statements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll need a list of any investments that you have, statements from your investment accounts, and statements from your retirement accounts. These will also be used to show reserves that may be required for you to get that approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The more information you bring, the more you’re set up for success.%20http://localhost:4000/q-what-do-you-need-to-get-a-home-loan-today.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The more information you bring, the more you’re set up for success.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tax returns will need to be presented, and you should be prepared to write a check for an appraisal fee, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The lender will typically do a credit report check on you to show how many bills you have, what your total debt is, and what it’s costing you each month to live.&lt;/strong&gt; This will help them determine how much you can afford for housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re paying or receiving child support, you’ll need proof of that. If you have unemployment or disability income, you’ll need proof of that, too. The more information you bring, the more you’re set up for success. &lt;strong&gt;When you meet with your lender,&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;the goal is to walk out with a pre-approval letter.&lt;/strong&gt; This will show sellers that you’re serious and give you more buying power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also make this process easier by uploading all of this information right into my real estate app that’s on your phone. If you don’t have it yet, you can download it &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.kw.com/KW1Q9P16Q/&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 13:22:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-do-you-need-to-get-a-home-loan-today.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/q-what-do-you-need-to-get-a-home-loan-today.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Pitfalls of Mispricing Your Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s3obrqHn60w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;There are three main pitfalls to incorrectly pricing your home. Here’s why each is a mistake you don’t want to make.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began selling real estate in 2002, so I’ve seen plenty of mistakes made in the real estate world. There are three main pitfalls you can experience from pricing your home incorrectly for the market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Your home can become the pivot house.&lt;/strong&gt; This is where an agent is showing the property, knowing it’s priced too high for the market. While they’re in the home, they’ll say to their buyers something like: “If you’re fond of this house at this price, wait until you see the next one that’s similar but costs less.” Buyers will walk into your home and soon pivot and leave. If yours is the pivot house, you’re simply helping the competition sell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. You’ll sit on the market.&lt;/strong&gt; When a home sits on the market for an extended period or longer than the average days on market, buyers start to ask questions like “What’s wrong with that house?” The property could end up with a stigma; you don’t want buyers asking that question about your home. Buyers may also ask if the house is overpriced. When this question is asked, if the buyer is interested, you’ll likely receive lowball offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If yours is the pivot house, you’re simply helping the competition sell.%20http://localhost:4000/3-pitfalls-of-mispricing-your-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If yours is the pivot house, you’re simply helping the competition sell.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Only getting one offer.&lt;/strong&gt; 80% to 90% of buyers have to get a mortgage to purchase a home, so their lender will order an appraisal. If the appraisal comes in low, that can cause drama for the seller. When you’re in the middle of a transaction and moving your family, who needs more trouble?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know the true value of your property and how to sell it for the right price, know that we’re here to serve. Call or email us if you have real estate needs or questions. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 16:36:06 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-pitfalls-of-mispricing-your-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-pitfalls-of-mispricing-your-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things to Do While Stuck at Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fvra869ay-w?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Looking for ways to keep busy at home? We've got you covered.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all staying home right now because it’s the right thing to do. Today we wanted to send some ideas of fun things you can do while stuck at home. Here are a few things you can do virtually: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCYyJUEtYv-ZW7BgjhP3UbTg/videos&quot;&gt;Walt Disney World&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.broadwayhd.com/&quot;&gt;Broadway&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yourtango.com/2018317900/15-best-free-yoga-videos-youtube-has-offer&quot;&gt;take digital yoga classes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chicago.curbed.com/2020/3/20/21188477/virtual-tour-chicago-museums-cultural-institutions-home&quot;&gt;take museum tours&lt;/a&gt;, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate is considered an essential service, so if we can help you with anything, please reach out to us. We have safety protocols in place to keep people healthy while still fulfilling your real estate needs. To hear my full message, watch this short video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 16:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/things-to-do-while-stuck-at-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/things-to-do-while-stuck-at-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
