<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Podcast with Mark Ramey</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Mark Ramey Group - your professional Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Mark Ramey</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-08-14 09:08:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Mark Ramey</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Team@themarkrameygroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Mark Ramey</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Dr. Phillips-Windermere Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Mark Ramey Group - your professional Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Comparing the Positive Aspects of Buying & Renting</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comparing-the-positive-aspects-of-buying-renting.html</link>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-08-06 16:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B17-23%5D+Buying+vs+Renting.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Which is better right now: buying or renting?

Given the state of our market and economy lately, many people have been reaching out to ask me the following question: Is it better to buy or rent?

“Homeownership allows you to personalize your home and make choices when it comes to decorating and remodeling.”

Let’s start with the positives of renting:

There’s no down payment. You simply have to come up with your first month’s rent and a security deposit, which can be less expensive than a down payment on a home.
You’re not responsible for maintenance—the landlord takes care of it all.
It’s a short-term obligation.
It gives you freedom to decide where you want to live on shorter notice.

Now, here are some of the pros of buying a home:

Rental rates are at an all-time high.
Mortgages are less than rent. After the down payment, mortgage payments are frequently less than rental rates, meaning that people can often get into a nicer property by buying it than they can by renting it.
You can pay your own debt. Instead of paying down someone else’s mortgage like you do when you rent, you can drop your own debt, which puts you one step closer to financial freedom.
The market appreciates. On average, properties in our area will appreciate anywhere between 3% and 5% each year. For a $200,000 property, that’s between $6,000 and $10,000 of potential annual appreciation.
It gives you freedom. Homeownership allows you to personalize your living space and make fun choices when it comes to decorating and remodeling.

If you have any more questions about whether it’s in your best interest to rent or purchase, consider me your resource. You can reach out to me via phone or email at any time.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B17-23%5D+Buying+vs+Renting.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B17-23%5D+Buying+vs+Renting.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Which is better right now: buying or renting?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Which is better right now: buying or renting?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do I Get My Kids Excited to Move?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-i-get-my-kids-excited-to-move.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-07-23 11:29:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B22-23%5D+How+to+Get+Kids+Excited+to+Move.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Moving is stressful for kids, so help them along with these great tips.

Moving is often very stressful for children. The first things they think about are giving up their friends and their favorite aspects of their current home. I want to share a few strategies that may make them feel more comfortable with the process. 

My first suggestion is getting them involved in the move from the beginning. Talk to them about the benefits they’ll receive from moving. Maybe it’s an extra room or a larger yard where they’ll have more space to play, or perhaps they’re getting a swimming pool. I’d be thrilled about that too!

You can also involve them in the house hunt. Bring them along as you’re looking for properties, make it a family event; this can be exciting for them. Additionally, you could ask them to help design their new bedroom by picking out a paint color or a new comforter. You should also spend some time in the new neighborhood and try to introduce them to some of the other children in the community so they feel welcomed and connected to it.

“Get children involved in the moving process from the beginning.”

You may also want to take them to their new school. Let them see it, experience a little of it, and get excited about it. 

If you have questions about preparing children to move or real estate in general, please feel free to call or email us. We would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B22-23%5D+How+to+Get+Kids+Excited+to+Move.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B22-23%5D+How+to+Get+Kids+Excited+to+Move.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Moving is stressful for kids, so help them along with these great tips.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Moving is stressful for kids, so help them along with these great tips.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Staying Connected</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/staying-connected.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-07-20 14:47:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Most of you know that my sister Christi and I work together at Keller Williams Classic Realty. I am mentioning this because I have been watching how families have been staying connected during the last few months. Wow, the world has changed.

The word Zoom is now an adjective (get on the Zoom meeting), a noun (everyone sign in for the Zoom) and a verb (we will be Zooming in 10 minutes). That has all happened since March and it doesn’t matter if you were born in 1930 or 2018, you all know what those mean! Personally, I have been suffering from Zoom fatigue (Holy Crap, now it’s a condition) and I am looking forward to a birthday party where I am actually in the room with the cake!

I have to admit though that there are some benefits to this new world we live in. One of them is that most of Christi and my family lives in Illinois and for the first time ever we had an Easter Zoom get-together with relatives neither of us had seen in years. Luckily the video quality on Zoom isn’t that good so we all looked just as young as the last time we saw each other. We have also been able to stay in contact with friends, clients and co-workers in a way that allows us to get a glimpse (literally) into their lives and living rooms. In a weird way, the need to stay apart has really made us more creative in finding ways to stay connected.

I will take that thought one step further and say that I have also noticed that same creativity has come through as people have adapted to this new world. Face masks that match outfits, people using their eyes to smile, and being able to count on at least 2 out of 10 shoppers at Publix correctly using the directional arrows for the grocery aisles.

Best of all I have realized how lucky I am to have Derek in my life. How great it is to be able to work with my sister every day and how blessed I am to have the best team of people working with me that I could imagine having. I have watched them all adapt to new systems, work environments and challenges that none of us saw coming. We may not be sitting in adjacent desks as much as we use to be but we are there for each other every day. So maybe the world hasn’t actually changed much at all.&nbsp; – Sincerely, Mark Ramey


</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Most of you know that my sister Christi and I work together at Keller Williams Classic Realty. I am mentioning this because I have been watching how families have been staying connected during the last few months. Wow, the world has changed.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Most of you know that my sister Christi and I work together at Keller Williams Classic Realty. I am mentioning this because I have been watching how families have been staying connected during the last few months. Wow, the world has changed.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Hassle-Free Way to Enroll My Kids in OCPS?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-hassle-free-way-to-enroll-my-kids-in-ocps.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-07-06 12:59:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B7-23%5D+Tips+for+Enrolling+in+Orange+County+Public+Schools.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Every parent wants to set their child up for success in school, and here’s how.

Moving is stressful enough, but getting your kids into that new school district can be a whole challenge unto itself. 

If your kids are returning to Orange County Public Schools or some of the surrounding schools that operate similarly, enrollment is made easier by the fact that the students—especially high schoolers—are allowed to choose their classes the year prior. 

The challenge that my husband Eric and I had, however, arose when we hosted two exchange students; Oliver was from the Czech Republic, and Thomas was from Brazil, but both of them arrived just one week before school started. When we went to go pick their classes, they didn’t know what was available to them, so it made the process stressful.

“If you take care of all of these things, your child will be set up for success in our wonderful Orange County schools!”

They also needed a student ID to obtain their student device (rather than rely on books, students in Orange County Public Schools operate using a device that gives them easy, centralized access to their teachers, assignments, and grades). 

Since I dropped the ball when it came to registration and having all of the necessary information prepared, Thomas and Oliver had to start their first day of school without a set schedule. To avoid the same snafu for your kids, remember the following: 


  Get a list of classes in advance so your kids know what’s available. 
  Make sure you register your child in time for them to be issued a student ID number. 
  Having that ID will give them timely access to their student device so they can practice using it before classes start. 
  Make sure they stay in the habit of keeping their device charged!


If you take care of all of these things, your child will be set up for success in our wonderful Orange County schools! Hopefully, you found this message helpful. 

If you have any questions about real estate, or if you’re thinking of buying or selling a home soon, you can always reach out to me via phone or email. I’m here to be a resource for you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B7-23%5D+Tips+for+Enrolling+in+Orange+County+Public+Schools.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B7-23%5D+Tips+for+Enrolling+in+Orange+County+Public+Schools.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Every parent wants to set their child up for success, and here’s how.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Every parent wants to set their child up for success, and here’s how.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Do People Stage Their Home Before Selling?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-do-people-stage-their-home-before-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-06-08 10:56:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B23-24%5D+_+Staging.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Home staging pays for itself because of these three facts.

Here are three reasons why staging your home is a benefit to your home sale:

1. Buyers will pay more. According to a recent survey by Moritz Research, 63% of homebuyers would be willing to pay a higher price for a home that is staged well and in good condition.

2. You can stand out among the competition. A properly staged home is particularly important in a market with a lot of inventory.

3. We can broaden the market. When a home is staged, it appeals to more buyers. The more buyers it appeals to, the more showings and offers.

If you have questions for me about these staging tips or anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B23-24%5D+_+Staging.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B23-24%5D+_+Staging.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Home staging pays for itself because of these three facts.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Home staging pays for itself because of these three facts.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Know If Renovations Are in Your Best Interest</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-know-if-renovations-are-in-your-best-interest.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-19 15:12:10 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/%5B1-23%5D+Should+You+Renovate+Before+You+Sell_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The first step in solving the renovation dilemma is knowing your home type.

When making a decision as to whether to make renovations on your home, I’d like you to consider which home you have in the marketplace. Generally, there are three types of homes that are selling in today’s market: 


  
    The first type of home is the brand-new home. Perhaps it’s a new build, or it recently underwent a complete overhaul renovation to thoroughly modernize it. This home will appeal to 99% of buyers in our marketplace.

  
    The second type of home is the one that’s in clean, move-in condition. It may need a few renovations to suit individual buyers’ tastes, but the basics are all up to par.

  
    The third type of home is the one that needs repair. It could sell as is, but whoever purchases it does so knowing that it will need some serious work.

“Simply painting and updating flooring can add anywhere from 10% to 15% to your home’s value.”

Selling the first home is fairly straightforward: I have my professional photographer come out to snap some stellar pictures, we get it on the market, and we get it sold. These types of homes usually sell quickly with little to no hassle.

The second type of home is just as desirable as the first in today’s market. Buyers may want to renovate a few areas upon moving in, but theoretically, a buyer could move in and not need to do any no serious work. For selling this type of home, I would just make sure that we have fresh coats of paint on the walls, and clean, new carpet or flooring. Also, check your home’s curb appeal; trim the shrubs, get some flowers in the garden, and put down some fresh mulch. Once you tackle these relatively easy improvements, you’ll already be in the best position on the market. Simply painting and updating flooring can add anywhere from 10% to 15% to your home’s value. 

For the third type of home, you have to anticipate making some hard choices. If you choose to do nothing to it, it will likely sell 20% to 30% below what Type 1 and Type 2 homes sell for. So, if you’re the owner of Type 3 and need to make some renovations, we have some amazing, fully vetted professionals that we’d love to connect you with. 

If you have any specific questions on this topic, or if you’d like me to show you what your home would likely go for on the market before and after certain renovations, please reach out to me by phone or email. I’m here to be a resource for you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/%5B1-23%5D+Should+You+Renovate+Before+You+Sell_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/%5B1-23%5D+Should+You+Renovate+Before+You+Sell_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The first step in solving the renovation dilemma is knowing your home type.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The first step in solving the renovation dilemma is knowing your home type.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Make Delicious Omelettes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-make-delicious-omelettes.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-13 13:19:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
    
        
    
    
        So, with the current state of the world I thought a nice sort of funny letter would be appropriate. During the weekends this last school year we would sometimes have one of the other exchange students come over and spend the weekend with Oliver and Thomas. One of their best friends from the exchange program was a young man named Andri from Switzerland. Needless to say, with all of these students in the house the warning sign to the left was appropriate. Derek would even say necessary.
        Andri was not the kind of young man who watched idly from the sidelines. He was always getting involved with everything going on around him.
    



    
        
    
    
        I couldn’t even make breakfast for him. As soon as I started making omelettes one morning, he was right there asking how I made them. I showed him how and he made them for all of us that morning and any other morning that he was at the house.
        Andri wrote the thank you letter to the left on the back of the above warning sign. His host mother brought it over after he had flown back to Switzerland while he still could.
        I don’t think any of us were expecting the students' exchanges to end so quickly but all three boys are back home safely with their families. I actually had to drive Thomas to Miami to get him on what seemed to be the last flight on the planet going to Brazil.
    


You might be wondering how to make delicious omelettes. It just takes practice until you can flip the eggs. Once you have that figured out, I suggest teaching it to someone else. You never know what can make a lasting memory. – Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In respect to our current climate of social distancing we thought that the easiest way to minimize points of contact in regards to sending out these letters would be to deliver them to you by email for the time being.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In respect to our current climate of social distancing we thought that the easiest way to minimize points of contact in regards to sending out these letters would be to deliver them to you by email for the time being.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Q: What Do You Need to Get a Home Loan Today?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/q-what-do-you-need-to-get-a-home-loan-today.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-05-05 13:22:35 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/Q-+What+Do+You+Need+to+Get+a+Home+Loan+Today_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

A pre-approval will give you a leg up as a homebuyer. Here is what you’ll need to get one.

Often I hear buyers ask, “What do I need to bring to my lender so that I can make an application for a loan?” Here’s your checklist.

First, you’ll need at least three months’ worth of bank statements. You’ll also need proof of down payment, which will come from those bank statements.

You’ll need a list of any investments that you have, statements from your investment accounts, and statements from your retirement accounts. These will also be used to show reserves that may be required for you to get that approval.

“The more information you bring, the more you’re set up for success.”

Tax returns will need to be presented, and you should be prepared to write a check for an appraisal fee, too.

The lender will typically do a credit report check on you to show how many bills you have, what your total debt is, and what it’s costing you each month to live. This will help them determine how much you can afford for housing.

If you’re paying or receiving child support, you’ll need proof of that. If you have unemployment or disability income, you’ll need proof of that, too. The more information you bring, the more you’re set up for success. When you meet with your lender, the goal is to walk out with a pre-approval letter. This will show sellers that you’re serious and give you more buying power.

You can also make this process easier by uploading all of this information right into my real estate app that’s on your phone. If you don’t have it yet, you can download it here.

If you have any questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/Q-+What+Do+You+Need+to+Get+a+Home+Loan+Today_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/Q-+What+Do+You+Need+to+Get+a+Home+Loan+Today_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>A pre-approval will give you a leg up as a homebuyer. Here is what you’ll need to get one.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>A pre-approval will give you a leg up as a homebuyer. Here is what you’ll need to get one.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Pitfalls of Mispricing Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-pitfalls-of-mispricing-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-21 16:36:06 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B22-24%5D+_+Pitfalls+of+Pricing+Too+High.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are three main pitfalls to incorrectly pricing your home. Here’s why each is a mistake you don’t want to make.

I began selling real estate in 2002, so I’ve seen plenty of mistakes made in the real estate world. There are three main pitfalls you can experience from pricing your home incorrectly for the market:

1. Your home can become the pivot house. This is where an agent is showing the property, knowing it’s priced too high for the market. While they’re in the home, they’ll say to their buyers something like: “If you’re fond of this house at this price, wait until you see the next one that’s similar but costs less.” Buyers will walk into your home and soon pivot and leave. If yours is the pivot house, you’re simply helping the competition sell. 

2. You’ll sit on the market. When a home sits on the market for an extended period or longer than the average days on market, buyers start to ask questions like “What’s wrong with that house?” The property could end up with a stigma; you don’t want buyers asking that question about your home. Buyers may also ask if the house is overpriced. When this question is asked, if the buyer is interested, you’ll likely receive lowball offers.

“If yours is the pivot house, you’re simply helping the competition sell.”

3. Only getting one offer. 80% to 90% of buyers have to get a mortgage to purchase a home, so their lender will order an appraisal. If the appraisal comes in low, that can cause drama for the seller. When you’re in the middle of a transaction and moving your family, who needs more trouble?

If you want to know the true value of your property and how to sell it for the right price, know that we’re here to serve. Call or email us if you have real estate needs or questions. We would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B22-24%5D+_+Pitfalls+of+Pricing+Too+High.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B22-24%5D+_+Pitfalls+of+Pricing+Too+High.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are three main pitfalls to incorrectly pricing your home. Here’s why each is a mistake you don’t want to make.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are three main pitfalls to incorrectly pricing your home. Here’s why each is a mistake you don’t want to make.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Things to Do While Stuck at Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/things-to-do-while-stuck-at-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-04-08 16:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Things+You+Can+Do.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Looking for ways to keep busy at home? We've got you covered.

We’re all staying home right now because it’s the right thing to do. Today we wanted to send some ideas of fun things you can do while stuck at home. Here are a few things you can do virtually: Walt Disney World, Broadway, take digital yoga classes, take museum tours, and more.

Real estate is considered an essential service, so if we can help you with anything, please reach out to us. We have safety protocols in place to keep people healthy while still fulfilling your real estate needs. To hear my full message, watch this short video.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Things+You+Can+Do.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Things+You+Can+Do.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We’re all staying home right now due to the health crisis. Today we’re sharing a few fun things you can do to pass the time.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We’re all staying home right now due to the health crisis. Today we’re sharing a few fun things you can do to pass the time.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The 4 Criteria That Will Determine Whether You Can Get a Loan</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-4-criteria-that-will-determine-whether-you-can-get-a-loan.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-03-09 15:35:52 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B21-24%5D+_+Can+I+Get+a+Home+Loan_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are four points to consider if you’re wondering whether you can qualify for a loan to purchase a home.

When I was 20 years old, my father asked me one day to get my bank book. Once I did, he told me I was buying a house. It scared the heck out of me, but he helped me understand four critical pieces of information that taught me I really could afford to buy a house. At the time, I didn’t have enough cash to buy, so I knew I needed a mortgage, and these four points were the criteria lenders used to determine whether I was qualified to buy—the same criteria used for buyers today.

So if you want to buy a house and aren’t sure whether you can get a loan, here are the four points to consider:

1. Income. Your income provides clarity on your ability to repay your loan. The lender will look at how much income you earn and how much you spend and calculate a ratio. If that ratio is a fit for the loan program, guess what? You get a loan! 

2. Credit. As with the previous point, your credit indicates your likelihood to repay the loan, and it’s all based on your past. Perhaps you’ve had some bumps in the road you need to correct, or perhaps you have a stellar credit history (which will work in your favor). In any case, most first-time homebuyers don’t have anything in their credit file, so it takes them a little time to build it up.

“Buying a home is easier than you think.”

3. The appraised value of the property you’re purchasing. This all boils down to the home’s value as determined by an appraiser. Between 80% and 90% of all buyers in today’s market have to obtain a mortgage, and their lender will require an appraisal for the property they’re buying to make sure they’re not paying too much for it. 

4. The cash you have. This means the lender will source the amount of money you have to ensure you have the right down payment, closing costs, and (sometimes) reserves in your bank account in case something happens and you no longer have a source of income. 

Remember—buying a home is easier than you think. If you have questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B21-24%5D+_+Can+I+Get+a+Home+Loan_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B21-24%5D+_+Can+I+Get+a+Home+Loan_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are four points to consider if you’re wondering whether you can qualify for a loan to purchase a home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are four points to consider if you’re wondering whether you can qualify for a loan to purchase a home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Sell Your Home, Part 2</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-your-home-part-2.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-21 15:31:10 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B20-24%5D+_+4+Ps+for+Selling+Part+2.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’m explaining the four Ps and how they’ll help get your home sold.

This message is part two in our series about both what to do and not to do when selling your home. There are four Ps my team and I follow to help our clients sell their houses:

1. Price. When we price your property correctly for the market, we drive buyers to that listing. The more buyers that show up, the more opportunities a seller has. That means there’s a greater chance the seller will receive multiple offers, which puts them in a position of strength to negotiate. 

2. Promotion. We want to promote your home aggressively. We will do everything we possibly can to benefit your sale. I belong to a network of the top 1% of all real estate agents in the U.S. and, this means we’re receiving highly qualified, motivated buyers who want to buy your house. These buyers will pay a fair retail price.

3. Presentation. A lot of this step is up to you. You’ll need to prepare your property by painting, fixing things, and making it look fresh. Sometimes this requires calling in a professional stager.

“I belong to a network of the top 1% of all real estate agents in the U.S.”

4. Prospect. We prospect every day proactively. We’re searching for the ideal buyer for your home. 

When these four Ps come together, they translate into wonderful results for you, your wallet, and your move. When selling your house, always remember the four Ps. 

If you have any other questions about the selling process or real estate in general, please contact me by phone or email. I would love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B20-24%5D+_+4+Ps+for+Selling+Part+2.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B20-24%5D+_+4+Ps+for+Selling+Part+2.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m explaining the four Ps and how they’ll help get your home sold.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m explaining the four Ps and how they’ll help get your home sold.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>There’s No Livin’ Like Lake Livin’</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/theres-no-livin-like-lake-livin.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-02-07 15:14:48 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Lake+living2.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here’s the lowdown on lakefront living in the greater Orlando area.

Here in Orlando, Florida, we truly do have some beautiful lake properties to offer. The one lake that everyone knows about is the very same people like to walk around in downtown Orlando: Lake Eola. 

Near Eola, you have condo living with some gorgeous high-rises offering stunning views and access to entertainment, limitless shopping options, and fine restaurants. 

In the Winter Park chain of lakes, there are six total lakes right in and around Rollins College and downtown Winter Park. Here, a variety of condo living options will provide you with easy access to all of them. There are also both residential and high-end luxury homes in those areas.

“Whether it’s Lake Eola downtown, or the seven lakes of Seminole, our area has plenty of waterfront action.”

Toward the eastern part of Orange County, there’s the Conway chain of lakes, consisting of four total lakes with some historical home sites and very reasonably priced lakefront properties. There’s also easy access to the airport from this area. 

In the Butler lakes (13 total), there are Dr. Phillips communities/areas like Turtle Creek and the Bay Hill Country Club, and Windermere communities like Keynes Point and Isleworth, each a high-end golf community. 

In College Park, you have Lake Fairview and Lake Silver, which lies in Seminole County. That county alone offers seven other wonderful lakes, Lake Brantley, Lake Jesup (note: the quantity of alligators in this one makes swimming an ill-advised activity), Lake Monroe (part of the St. Johns river system), Lake Oriental in Altamonte Springs, Lake Mary, Lake Howell, and Bear Lake in Apopka. 

For more information about lakefront living, please consider me as a resource. Call me or send an email at any time. It would be a privilege to talk with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Lake+living2.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Lake+living2.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s the lowdown on lakefront living in the greater Orlando area.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s the lowdown on lakefront living in the greater Orlando area.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How NOT to Advertise Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-not-to-advertise-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-23 16:35:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B16-24%5D+_+Bad+Real+Estate+Advertising.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I’m sharing some examples of horrible advertising that we will never use for your home. Join us for some laughs at these awful ads.

Today I’m sharing bad advertising that I promise we will never use when marketing your home. Starting at 0:15 in the video above, see some examples of some truly atrocious advertising. 

These real for sale signs say:


  “For the love of God, would someone buy this house?!” These owners sound a little desperate, huh?
  “Zombie Free!” It’s critical in today’s world to think about safety. 
  “Owner ready to croak, must sell.” They should probably get that person to the emergency room…
  “House for sale because my neighbor’s an asshole!” How do they really feel?
  “Husband left us for a 22-year-old. House for sale by slightly bitter, newly single owner.” I’m not sure I want to hear the rest of that story.
  “For sale, mice included.” What else does this house come with?
  “New flats for rent: 2 rooms + hall + 1 bathroom + chicken.” A new pet comes with this rental, how thoughtful!
  “Wraparound porch, storm/wine cellar, spectacular room to grow marijuana, open floor plan.” In case recreational marijuana ever becomes legal in Florida. 


Don’t worry, we’ll never use advertising like this for your home. You can count on us for care and good advice. Thanks for sharing some laughs with us today! If you have questions about how to get your home sold the right way, it would be a privilege to help you. Reach out to us by phone or email at your convenience.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B16-24%5D+_+Bad+Real+Estate+Advertising.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B16-24%5D+_+Bad+Real+Estate+Advertising.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m sharing some examples of horrible advertising that we will never use for your home. Join us for some laughs at these awful ads.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m sharing some examples of horrible advertising that we will never use for your home. Join us for some laughs at these awful ads.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Mistakes to Avoid When Selling: Part 1</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-mistakes-to-avoid-when-selling-part-1.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-06 14:42:01 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B19-24%5D+_+3+Mistakes+When+Selling+Part+1.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Here are three mistakes to avoid when selling your home.

When it comes to selling a home, sometimes we don’t know the finer points of how to go about it. Here are three mistakes to avoid when selling your house:

1. Asking too much. When a property is priced too high it tends to sit on the market. When a home sits on the market for an extended period, longer than what is common for the market, buyers begin to ask their Realtors questions about it. What’s wrong with the house? Is the home overpriced? These buyers may not even give your house a chance.

“Your home must make a great first impression.”

2. Advertising too little. We can’t advertise enough in today’s market to ensure no stone is unturned to find you the right buyer.

3. Not making a good first impression. You want to make sure your home shows well so people will want to purchase it. 98% of our buyers want a house they can simply move into and live in right away. So, your home must make a great first impression.

If you have further questions about this or any other real estate topic, please reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B19-24%5D+_+3+Mistakes+When+Selling+Part+1.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2020/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B19-24%5D+_+3+Mistakes+When+Selling+Part+1.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here are three mistakes to avoid when selling your home.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here are three mistakes to avoid when selling your home.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Lost in Translation</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/lost-in-translation.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-01 10:56:29 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Hosting two exchange students from different parts of the world can have its challenges. Language, primarily English not being either of their primary languages, is one of those challenges.  It is also one of the main reasons that most students do an exchange for an entire school year in the United States, to become proficient in English. 

  
    Our student from Brazil, Thomas, taught himself English by watching television and movies.&nbsp; He is actually pretty good but we work a lot on sounds that his mouth physically has trouble creating.&nbsp; Just like it is really hard for me to roll my rrrrs like they do in so many of the Latin languages (he speaks Portuguese) Thomas finds it very difficult to create the ld sound. An example would be the word world. Thomas says something closer to woooold.&nbsp; His mouth just can’t create the physical configuration that produces the correct sound.&nbsp; I can’t tell you how many dinners we have all laughed while we tried to say words from each other’s language.&nbsp; It is a lot of fun to hear his progress as he gets closer to being able to say world.&nbsp;
  
  
    
  

Speaking English is, of course, only half of the challenge.  Understanding it is a whole other story.  Not long after the boys first arrived, Derek asked Thomas to bring his bed sheets to the laundry room.  Thomas smiled, said yes, and headed to his room.  When he didn’t return for quite a while, Derek went to his room, pointed at his bed and asked him again to bring his sheets to the laundry room.  Thomas also pointed at the bed and said yes.  The next thing I saw was Thomas walking toward the laundry room carrying his sheets, pillow cases, mattress pad, blanket, quilt and shams.  I honestly think that his plan was to drop off that load and go back and get the mattress.  Not only did he not understand what sheets were, he also didn’t understand the concept of washing them.  Apparently this had been taken care of for him.  Let’s just say Derek took care of that little educational moment right away.

Little things also happen that really make you think about how much we assume people understand.  Now Oliver, our other exchange student from Czechia, learned English in Great Britain.  We have a lot of fun with him because you never know what accent he will be using from the regions he travelled through. This last holiday season we took both of the boys to St. Augustine to see the lights and to tour Flagler College.  As we entered the lady’s reception lounge our guide pointed out the eleven priceless Austrian crystal Tiffany chandeliers that hang from the ceiling.  Oliver turned to us with a weird look on his face and asked us why they were priceless. 

  
    We explained to him how an item that cannot be replaced can be considered priceless.&nbsp; He continued to look at us like we were crazy.&nbsp; It took us a few minutes but we finally figured out that he was translating *priceless* to *worthless* (or without value).&nbsp; Here we were having this entire conversation as to why the chandeliers were priceless, and all he is hearing is us trying to justify why something of great beauty and value is worthless.&nbsp; Two completely opposite conversations because one word was lost in translation.&nbsp;&nbsp;
  
  
    
  

We are living in a moment of time that has an abundance of words, headlines and statements.  All of these words mean different things to different people. If the experience of hosting these two students has taught me anything it is that being proficient in English is just the start.  Learning how to listen, how to ask good questions and how to use our words to bring about a clear understanding for ourselves and others.  Those are skills that are truly priceless in any language.  

Sincerely, Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Hosting two exchange students from different parts of the world can have its challenges. Language, primarily English not being either of their primary languages, is one of those challenges.  It is also one of the main reasons that most students do an exchange for an entire school year in the United States, to become proficient in English.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Hosting two exchange students from different parts of the world can have its challenges. Language, primarily English not being either of their primary languages, is one of those challenges.  It is also one of the main reasons that most students do an exchange for an entire school year in the United States, to become proficient in English.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Fulfill the New Year’s Resolution of Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-fulfill-the-new-years-resolution-of-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-19 11:15:24 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B17-24%5D+_+New+Years+Resolution.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If your New Year’s resolution is to sell your home, these six tips will help you make it possible. Here’s what to do.

The new year is right around the corner, and many people have already made the resolution to sell their home. Here are some ways you can ensure your home selling resolution is fulfilled in 2020:

1. Get a comparative market analysis of your home. This will help you learn more about your home’s value and the equity you can use for your next home purchase.

2. Understand your where, why, and when. You want to know where you’re moving, why you’re moving, and when you want to move. Understanding these factors helps your move to be better planned and more purposeful.

3. Get pre-approved. If you’re not paying cash for your next home, it’s a good idea to get a mortgage pre-approval. This helps you understand the numbers and know exactly what you can afford.

“You want to know where you’re moving, why you’re moving, and when you want to move.”

4. Understand your moving situation. Some people don’t sell their home until they’ve already found a new one. If you buy a home while still selling your first one, you may own two properties at the same time. If you buy a home and sell yours simultaneously, you can move right in without looking for temporary housing.

5. Have a staging consultation. Staging your home makes it more appealing to buyers. We typically either do it ourselves or pay a professional staging company to do it.

6. List with an agent that cares about you. Your Realtor should help you accomplish your family’s goals, dreams, and real estate aspirations.

If you have any questions or would like information, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B17-24%5D+_+New+Years+Resolution.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B17-24%5D+_+New+Years+Resolution.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If your New Year’s resolution is to sell your home, these six tips will help you make it possible. Here’s what to do.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If your New Year’s resolution is to sell your home, these six tips will help you make it possible. Here’s what to do.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>See the Highlights of Our Fall Fest Client Event</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/see-the-highlights-of-our-fall-fest-client-event.html</link>
        
          <category>The Mark Ramey Group</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-12-05 10:29:58 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Fall+Fest+Client+Appreciation+Event.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our Fall Fest Client Event was a smashing success, and we want to show you the highlights.

As you know, we recently held our Fall Fest Client Appreciation Event at the Orange County Sportsman Associate on Lake Sheen, and we’re proud to say it was a huge success.

We had around 60 guests stop by and we provided plenty of BBQ and entertainment for the whole family to enjoy. On that note, we want to congratulate the winners of our cornhole tournament, Doug Smith and Ammer Khan, and the winners of our Bingo tournament. 

You can check out all the photos we took of this event here. If you came, we were glad to have you join us. If not, we hope to see you at our next client event. In the meantime, if you have any real estate needs at all, call or email us anytime. We’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Fall+Fest+Client+Appreciation+Event.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Fall+Fest+Client+Appreciation+Event.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our Fall Fest Client Event was a smashing success, and we want to show you the highlights.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our Fall Fest Client Event was a smashing success, and we want to show you the highlights.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Thanksgiving Gratitude</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/thanksgiving-gratitude.html</link>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-12 14:40:37 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/Thanksgiving+Gratitude.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today I&rsquo;m sharing GEMs&mdash;a tool I use every day to help me experience a more peaceful life.

It’s Thanksgiving time, and I wanted to share something that has helped me in my life. It’s all wrapped around a daily habit of gratitude. Each day when I wake up I spend time writing in my journal. I do something my mentor shared with me called GEMs. This stands for gratitude, experience, and manifestations. 

“GEM stands for gratitude, experience, and manifestations.”

Since I’ve been writing these over the last few years, it has helped me bring incredible things into my life. Since this small, powerful tool has helped me, out of gratitude for all of you, I wanted to share it:

Gratitude. Each morning I write in my journal what I’m grateful for. I’ve learned that it’s impossible for me to have an experience of gratitude at the same time as fear. So, I also use this as a tool. If there’s ever anything that’s on my mind that may be causing me not to sleep, I write it down as a gratitude, and it causes that fear to dissipate.

Experience. Next, I write what I want to experience for the day. For example, that might sound like: “Today I intend to experience peace, clarity, focus, and joy.”

Manifestations. These are the material things and those that are meaningful to our lives and the lives of the people around us. For example, that might sound like: “Today I intend to manifest three listings from great clients.” 

At this time of the year, it’s important to express gratitude to the people who are significant to me, like you. I wish you all a happy Thanksgiving!

If you have any further questions about GEMs or concerning real estate, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to help you with whatever you need.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/Thanksgiving+Gratitude.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/Thanksgiving+Gratitude.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m sharing GEMs—a tool I use every day to help me experience a more peaceful life.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m sharing GEMs—a tool I use every day to help me experience a more peaceful life.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Space for Something New</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-space-for-something-new.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-11 10:40:24 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>The Space for Something New

With the school year well under way, I have been asked a few times if Derek and I had decided to host another Rotary exchange student this year.  I am happy to report that we are now hosting two Rotary Youth exchange students.  Thomas is a 17-year-old young man from Brazil and Oliver is a 17-year-old young man from a small village outside of Prague in Czechia.  We had the normal bumps at the beginning of the year (submitting homework on a laptop and going from a school of 400 students to 4000 students) but overall everything has gone smoothly.  

One thing that neither Derek nor I quite expected was the sheer amount of food two 17-year-old boys can eat.  It is staggering.  I am trying to think of another word that can describe it but staggering is the best one I can come up with.  We discovered that The Golden Corral buffet is pretty much the only way to actually fill them up.  The first time we took them there we noticed that the people sitting at the adjacent table were tracking how many times the boys were going back to the buffet.  At one point, one of them literally shouted “you’ve got to be kidding” as they headed back for more.  Personally, I think The Golden Corral is rethinking their whole business model. 

Now I don’t want you to think that the boys only eat, they are really great kids and they always want to help us with whatever project we are working on.  Since there have been a few teaser days of cooler weather, Derek has had both of them out in the garden getting everything ready for the winter plants.  One of the tasks that Derek asked their assistance with was clearing one the planters from weeds that had grown in over the summer.  The regular weeds were pretty easy but there were quite a few bamboo shoots coming up in the planter.  Derek explained that they would need to be dug out because the roots go all the way to China.  The two of them were feeling pretty strong so they tried to pull them out by hand.  When that didn’t work, they got the shovel, and they couldn’t believe how strong and deep the root systems of the bamboo proved to be.  They looked at the ground and on the surface it looked like nothing was there, but just under the top layer of soil there was a quagmire of the toughest roots you can imagine.   

Derek explained that anytime you want to plant a new garden you have to turn the soil and remove the old roots.  It is possible to cut the new flowers into the old root system, and they will look fine for a while, but eventually the old root system will choke out the new plants and you end up with a sad flower garden.  They took a shovel to cut a line around the planter they were working with.  There are roots everywhere and to try and dig them all up is futile, so he told them to just stick with the area that they wanted to replant. Once the edge was cut, they worked their way together toward the middle.  They dug up the dirt, cut through the roots and pulled them out as they found them.  It was hard work but the soil base of a planter is the foundation of a garden.  Once they had everything cleared away, the new flowers went in with the space to have their own roots flourish. 

  
    To me, fall seems more like spring in Florida.&nbsp; It cools down just enough that you want to get outside and start something new.&nbsp; If you feel the same way, I have some simple advice for you.&nbsp; You have to create the space for something new to happen in your life.&nbsp; You have to look under the surface and see what’s holding you where you are, and if you decide you would rather be doing something else, rip those roots out and plant some new ones.&nbsp;
  
  
    
  


Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>With the school year well under way, I have been asked a few times if Derek and I had decided to host another Rotary exchange student this year.  I am happy to report that we are now hosting two Rotary Youth exchange students.  Thomas is a 17-year-old young man from Brazil and Oliver is a 17-year-old young man from a small village outside of Prague in Czechia.  We had the normal bumps at the beginning of the year (submitting homework on a laptop and going from a school of 400 students to 4000 students) but overall everything has gone smoothly.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>With the school year well under way, I have been asked a few times if Derek and I had decided to host another Rotary exchange student this year.  I am happy to report that we are now hosting two Rotary Youth exchange students.  Thomas is a 17-year-old young man from Brazil and Oliver is a 17-year-old young man from a small village outside of Prague in Czechia.  We had the normal bumps at the beginning of the year (submitting homework on a laptop and going from a school of 400 students to 4000 students) but overall everything has gone smoothly.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How You Can Get Involved With United Against Poverty’s Upcoming Toy Drive</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-you-can-get-involved-with-united-against-povertys-upcoming-toy-drive.html</link>
        
          <category>Toy Drive</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-05 09:32:54 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Toy+Drive.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The local charity organization United Against Poverty is hosting a toy drive in the near future. Here’s everything you need to know.

Recently I had the privilege of speaking with Nancy Robbinson of United Against Poverty to discuss the organization’s goal, her role as development officer, and their upcoming toy drive. This discussion was so enlightening that I wanted to share it with all of you, as well. 

Cited below for your convenience is an outline of our discussion, with timestamps so that you can skip ahead to the section(s) that interest you the most:

0:05 - An introduction to today’s interview

0:20 - Nancy describes her role in United Against Poverty

0:39 - Nancy shares a few words on United Against Poverty’s upcoming toy drive

3:10 - How to donate toys at (or after) my upcoming client appreciation event

4:06 - How United Against Poverty helps families lift themselves up into economic self-sufficiency and how you can help with this goal

If you have any other questions about United Against Poverty, check out their website: https://unitedagainstpoverty.org/. And, as always, if you would like to discuss your real estate goals, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Toy+Drive.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Toy+Drive.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The local charity organization United Against Poverty is hosting a toy drive in the near future. Here’s everything you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The local charity organization United Against Poverty is hosting a toy drive in the near future. Here’s everything you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Selling a Home Now vs. Selling a Home in the Spring</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/selling-a-home-now-vs-selling-a-home-in-the-spring.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-31 13:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B6-23%5D+Sell+Now+or+Wait+Till+Spring_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Does it make more sense to sell your home now or wait until spring? Here’s what I think.

If you want to sell your home, should you start the process now or wait until spring? I’m here to answer this question today.

We’re in Orlando, which means we don’t have the snow and other cold weather conditions that affect our market. As a result, we pretty much have an even flow of buyers throughout the year. However, there are some slight peaks and valleys. For example, we typically have a little bit lower inventory around this time of year. 

Lower inventory means buyers have less to choose from. When there’s less to choose from, those truly motivated buyers can tend to be a little more emotional. Less competition and more emotional buyers typically equal a higher sales price for a home.

A warmly decorated home around the holidays can create a fantastic effect when it comes to staging and showing. 

On the flip side of these benefits, you may simply not want your holiday festivities with your family interrupted, so you’ll have to consider that, too.

“Less competition and more emotional buyers equal a higher sales price.”

Let’s say that you want to wait until spring- what will you find there? Typically there will be more buyers, and the yards will be in full bloom, but there will be more inventory as well.

If you have any other questions for me about when the best time for you to buy or sell a home is, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B6-23%5D+Sell+Now+or+Wait+Till+Spring_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B6-23%5D+Sell+Now+or+Wait+Till+Spring_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Does it make more sense to sell your home now or wait until spring? Here’s what I think.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Does it make more sense to sell your home now or wait until spring? Here’s what I think.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Questions First-Time Buyers Must Ask Themselves Before Buying</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/questions-first-time-buyers-must-ask-themselves-before-buying.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-11 11:36:41 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Before embarking on your first home purchase, here are the questions you must ask yourself.

If you’re thinking of buying a home, there are certain questions you must ask yourself first in order to know whether you’re making the right choice. 

1. Are you financially prepared? 

If a buyer doesn’t have the cash to purchase a home outright, they do so with a mortgage. To get a mortgage, you generally need a credit score of at least 620, and it takes money to raise or correct your credit score if it doesn’t meet that mark. 

When using a mortgage, you’ll have to make a down payment, which usually makes up anywhere from 3% to 20% of the overall purchase price of the home. After that, you have to pay closing costs, which make up 3% to 4% of the purchase price. If you bought a $200,000 home, for example, your closing costs would equal roughly $6,000.

2. Are you prepared to make compromises? 

Let’s say your approved value (i.e., what you can get financing for) is $200,000 but you’re looking to buy in a location where home prices average at least $250,000. Would you be willing to buy in another location or buy a fixer-upper? These are things you’ll want to consider. 

“To get a mortgage, you generally need a credit score of at least 620.”

3. Will owning a home pay off in the long run? 

When I was 20 years old and living at home, my dad asked me to get my bank book (a book you took to the bank to keep your financial balances current). When he looked at my bank book, he told me I was going to buy a property. I was scared to death, but it was the best thing he could’ve asked me to do. I ended up buying a condo for $94,000 that I later sold for $120,000. Realizing the gain from that appreciation—money I didn’t even have to work for—gave me the resources to buy my next home, which was an awesome loft in a trendy part of town. 

These are the benefits homeownership brings, but you have to know whether you’re making the best decision for yourself, first. Also, keep in mind that when you own a home, you’re responsible for the maintenance, which is another issue entirely. 

If you’d like to talk more about whether you should make the leap to homeownership or you have any questions about the home buying process, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+First-Time+Homebuyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Before embarking on your first home purchase, here are the questions you must ask yourself.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Before embarking on your first home purchase, here are the questions you must ask yourself.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Tips to Help You Prepare For Hurricane Season</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tips-to-help-you-prepare-for-hurricane-season.html</link>
        
          <category>Hurricane Prep</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-05 08:49:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B10-23%5D+Tips+to+Prepare+for+Hurricane+Season.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Whether we like it or not, it’s hurricane season. Here are some tips that can help you protect yourself as a homebuyer and a homeowner.

Hurricane season is upon us, unfortunately. However, even with rough weather impending there are still things you can do both as a homeowner and as a homebuyer to protect yourself and your home this season.

First, let’s talk about what you can do to protect yourself as you’re buying a home during hurricane season.

One of the biggest things to make sure you have is proper insurance. The insurance industry has what’s known as a box—they draw a box on a map that extends from the northern end of Virginia down the east coast of Florida to Cuba and then back up the west coast of Florida to Virginia (see 0:54 in the video above for a pictorial representation of this box). 

If there is a named storm in this box when you have a scheduled closing and you don’t have your insurance policy written already, then you may not be able to close on it. That means when you’re buying a house, you’ll want to make sure that you have an extension put in place so that you’re still under contract when the storm hits.

Of course, the types of coverage you’ll want to have in place are flood, wind, and hurricane coverage. You’ll also want to check into the deductible. In many cases, deductibles for these types of coverages can be quite high—sometimes as high as 2% of a home’s value. On a $300,000 house, that can be a $6,000 deductible, so be prepared for that.

“I only want you and your family to be safe throughout this hurricane season.”

Now, let’s talk about what current homeowners can do to protect themselves for when the storm hits.

Like homebuyers, you’ll want to make sure that you have appropriate insurance coverage well before hurricane season hits.

Additionally, keep the following things on hand:


  Bottled water
  Non-perishable food in case the power goes out
  Extra batteries and flashlights, perhaps even candles
  A battery-operated radio
  A generator, if feasible
  Bags of ice and coolers to store food
  A five-gallon bucket for bathing and other purposes


Hopefully this information is useful to you. I only want you and your family to be safe throughout this hurricane season. If you have any further questions about preparing yourself for hurricane season, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. Stay safe out there!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B10-23%5D+Tips+to+Prepare+for+Hurricane+Season.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B10-23%5D+Tips+to+Prepare+for+Hurricane+Season.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Whether we like it or not, it’s hurricane season. Here are some tips that can help you protect yourself as a homebuyer and a homeowner.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Whether we like it or not, it’s hurricane season. Here are some tips that can help you protect yourself as a homebuyer and a homeowner.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is There a Right Time to Put Your Orlando Home on the Market?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-there-a-right-time-to-put-your-orlando-home-on-the-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-04 09:45:42 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+When+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Sell.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There actually is a “right” time to sell your home—but when that is might surprise you.

“When the best time of year to sell my home?” 

I’ve been asked this question many times by sellers and those just entertaining the idea of selling their home. Here in the Orlando region, we enjoy the luxury of not having a seasonally dependent market. That means we see significant sales throughout the year and aren’t exposed to harsh weather that tends to diminish buyer motivation. Because of this, we don’t hit major lows in sales activity.

“The best time to sell a home is when it feels right for you.”

When kids are out of school between May and the end of July, we might see something like a 10% spike in our buyer pool, which temporarily drives demand up a bit. Otherwise, our market remains strong all year long! 

Therefore, the best time to sell a home is when it feels right for you. Whenever that time is, we’ll be here to serve you. It would be a privilege. 

If you have any questions or would like to discuss this further, please don’t hesitate to contact us. We look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+When+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Sell.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+When+Is+the+Best+Time+to+Sell.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There actually is a “right” time to sell your home—but when that is might surprise you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There actually is a “right” time to sell your home—but when that is might surprise you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Low Interest Rates Are Important for Buyers and Sellers</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-low-interest-rates-are-important-for-buyers-and-sellers.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-23 11:38:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+How+Low+Interest+Rates+Affect+You.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Low interest rates are good for buyers, but they’re also good for sellers. Here’s why.

When we’re talking about interest rates, their importance really comes down to one thing: affordability. For every point that interest rates go up or down, it affects the buying power of buyers by 10%. 

For example, if you are approved for $300,000 and interest rates go down by 1%, you can now afford $330,000. That’s significant.

What does this mean for home sellers? Essentially, it means there are more buyers and more competition for your home. This gives you a greater chance of receiving multiple offers and being able to negotiate from a position of strength. This will also allow you to choose the best price and the best terms. 

If you’re a buyer, you still have to be in a position where you can compete effectively. You need to be working with a good agent who is going to make sure you win and give you a competitive advantage in the market.

“There are more buyers and more competition for your home if you’re a seller.”

Before you get out there into the marketplace, let’s check in with the interest rates and make sure you’re tied in with a lender who is going to serve you best.

If you have any other questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+How+Low+Interest+Rates+Affect+You.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+How+Low+Interest+Rates+Affect+You.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Low interest rates are good for buyers, but they’re also good for sellers. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Low interest rates are good for buyers, but they’re also good for sellers. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What’s Going on in Real Estate Right Now?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-going-on-in-real-estate-right-now.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-12 09:47:31 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+market+update+8.1.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve got a short and sweet market update for you today. Here’s what you need to know.

Today I am going to give you a mid-year review on our real estate market to give you a better idea of what’s going on. Here’s what you need to know.

Inventory is low right now. While six months of inventory is considered a balanced market, we have about a 2.7-month supply in our market right now. This tells us that we’re in a seller’s market, which is great news for homeowners. In a seller’s market, prices are driven up. When you couple that with a drop in interest rates, you can see how our market is being fueled for sellers.

“We are working with homebuyers who are in desperate need of homes.”

Because inventory is so low, we’re having a difficult time finding homes for some of the families that we’re working with. Could you or someone you know benefit from selling right now? If so, we might already have some eager buyers who are interested in a home like yours.

If you have any questions about the latest numbers and what they mean for you, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+market+update+8.1.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+market+update+8.1.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’ve got a short and sweet market update for you today. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’ve got a short and sweet market update for you today. Here’s what you need to know.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Top 3 Renovations You Should Make if You’re Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-top-3-renovations-you-should-make-if-youre-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-18 16:06:26 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+renovations+when+selling.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re putting your home on the market, there are three types of renovations you can make that will appeal to the most buyers.

Did you know that roughly 98% of all buyers prefer move-in ready homes? If you’re putting your home on the market soon, here are the three types of renovations you can make that will turn your home into exactly what these buyers are looking for:

1. Add fresh paint to the interior and exterior. A fresh coat of neutral paint added to the interior of your home can go a long way, and it can also eliminate any lingering odors, which leads me to my next point…

2. Install fresh flooring (i.e., carpeting). A lot of sellers ask me whether they should add new wooden or laminate floors. Frankly, if you replace your current flooring with clean, neutral carpeting, that will create an appealing scent in your home. The least expensive flooring you can buy will be your best option, depending on your home. If you have an upscale home, you’re better off looking at other options. 

“A fresh coat of neutral paint added to the interior of your home can go a long way.”

3. Resolve any deferred maintenance. I’m talking about any broken windows, holes in the drywall, leaks (or stains from those leaks), etc. The last thing you want is a buyer to notice a hole in your drywall or something similar that will make them question whether you’ve kept your home in decent shape. You don’t want any questions or doubts in their mind before they make an offer. 

If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.  
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+renovations+when+selling.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+renovations+when+selling.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re putting your home on the market, there are three types of renovations you can make that will appeal to the most buyers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re putting your home on the market, there are three types of renovations you can make that will appeal to the most buyers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>It Isn't Always Everything or Nothing</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/it-isnt-always-everything-or-nothing.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-07 11:48:53 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>It isn’t always everything or nothing

  
    
  
    
    In 2006 Derek and I adopted 2 Siamese cats, a brother and sister.&nbsp; Some of you will remember that the brother, Luke Skywalker, passed away last year.&nbsp; His sister Tabitha recently got her own cat stroller and I thought you might enjoy the story.
    After Luke passed away we noticed that Tabitha was meowing a lot at what seemed to be nothing. She was also continuously running into walls and pretty much anything that was in front of her.&nbsp; After the fourth time of drying her off because she walked right into the swimming pool we decided to have her eyes checked.&nbsp; Let’s just say that it wasn’t a surprise when our vet told us that she is pretty much blind.&nbsp; Now all of the near misses of the litter box actually made sense!!!
  


Tabitha’s new world is a lot smaller.  We created a little cat spa in our bathroom with a cat bed, litter box and food and water dishes.  She is safe from falling in the pool and even her near misses on the tile are much easier to clean up.  The only problem is that the Tabitha we have always known wouldn’t stand for a small world.  She would have jumped over that baby gate without missing a beat, ran out the cat door to the pool deck and talked squirrel to the cardinals.  If you have ever owned a cat you will know what that means. 

The hard part for us was accepting that this is Tabitha’s new normal.  That sleeping in her cat bed under the light of the skylight is her new basking in the sun and that pretending that she can’t find that litter box because she is blind is acceptable.  I keep telling her that if I can smell the litter box, she can smell the litter box so please use the litter box!! 

It was during one of these one-way discussions of what is not acceptable that I realized that Tabitha hasn’t lost everything.  She may not be able to see but she can still smell, hear and feel.  I had seen a woman recently with a dog in a stroller so Derek and I went to Petco and we purchased a pet stroller.  Yes, I can confirm that there is a pet version of everything.  My hope was to try and give Tabitha a sense of freedom where she could use the senses that she still has to enjoy a slightly larger world.

There was “some assembly required” so it took a few minutes and choice words to get everything together but that same evening we took Tabitha on her first stroll of the neighborhood.  She may not have been able to see it but she could smell the rain storm that had just passed, hear the crickets in the trees and feel the slightly humid breeze.  It wasn’t everything, but it was definitely more than nothing.  

Life can change fast, and accepting what the new normal is can be hard.  I am so inspired by Tabitha’s willingness to just be.  It reminds me that sometimes the best quality of life can be found somewhere between everything and nothing.  Realizing that can actually bring some peace to your soul.  It doesn’t always have to be about what you can’t do. Sometimes it is as simple as finding the joy in what you can, and knowing that it is enough. 

Sincerely,

Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In 2006 Derek and I adopted 2 Siamese cats, a brother and sister.  Some of you will remember that the brother, Luke Skywalker, passed away last year.  His sister Tabitha recently got her own cat stroller and I thought you might enjoy the story.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In 2006 Derek and I adopted 2 Siamese cats, a brother and sister.  Some of you will remember that the brother, Luke Skywalker, passed away last year.  His sister Tabitha recently got her own cat stroller and I thought you might enjoy the story.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Make These Renovations if You Plan to Stay in Your Home for a While</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/make-these-renovations-if-you-plan-to-stay-in-your-home-for-awhile.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-02 11:19:06 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Renovations+When+Keeping+Part+1.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Which renovations should you make if you plan to stay in your home for a while? Let’s find out.

Which renovations are worth making to your home? Actually, the answer depends on whether you plan to keep it or sell it, so we’ll be covering each scenario in a two-part video series. For today’s message, which marks the first half of this series, we’ll talk about the renovations you should make if you plan to continue living in your home for some time.

“Even small renovations can make a big difference in the look and feel of your home.”

First on our list are kitchen and bathroom renovations. Installing a new kitchen or bathroom is one of the best investments you can make for your personal lifestyle and enjoyment. Adding new flooring throughout your home can also be a wise move, as can installing a new HVAC system. Both of these things will increase your level of comfort while living in the home. 

Finally, consider creating a more functional outdoor living space and working on your landscaping. These renovations, which can be done relatively inexpensively, can make a big difference in the look and feel of your home.

If you’d like to learn about the renovations you should make if you plan to sell, stay tuned for part two. Otherwise, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Renovations+When+Keeping+Part+1.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Renovations+When+Keeping+Part+1.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Which renovations should you make if you plan to stay in your home for a while? Let’s find out.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Which renovations should you make if you plan to stay in your home for a while? Let’s find out.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Zillow’s Zestimates Are Calculated</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-zillows-zestimates-are-calculated.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-18 09:52:33 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+zillow.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Does Zillow’s Zestimate accurately portray the value of your home? Find out today.

How does Zillow come up with their Zestimates?

They use a computer algorithm that gathers public data about the home sales that took place in your neighborhood within a certain period of time. Using this data and basic information about your home, they generate an estimation of your home’s value.

What Zillow doesn’t do, however, is personally come out to view your home. They have no way of knowing whether you’ve made any improvements to the property, like a new kitchen or new floors. They also don’t know if your neighbor’s home is in ill-repair, or what condition your property is currently in. All these points do factor into your home’s actual market value.

Here at the Mark Ramey Group, we can provide you with an accurate comparative market analysis based on the information you provided us about your home in its current condition—this is a true representation of your home’s market value.

“They have no way of knowing whether you’ve made any improvements to the property, like a new kitchen or new floors.”

If you have any questions about your home’s value or anything related to real estate at all, feel free to reach out to us. We’d love the privilege of being your real estate resource.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+zillow.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+zillow.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Does Zillow’s Zestimate accurately portray the value of your home? Find out today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Does Zillow’s Zestimate accurately portray the value of your home? Find out today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Movie Night Reminder and a Quick Question</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-movie-night-reminder-and-a-quick-question.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-31 14:56:22 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Movie+Night+Reminder.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you haven’t gotten tickets to movie night yet, make sure you do soon. If you know someone who is thinking about selling their home, you might also be able to win $300.

We just wanted to quickly reach out to remind you about our upcoming movie night. If you haven’t already received your invite to “Toy Story 4” and “Dark Phoenix,” please RSVP by giving us a call or sending us an email today, because seats are filling up fast.

Also, we’re currently working with six really good families and inventory is so low that we’re having trouble finding homes for them. Can you or someone you know benefit from selling your home right now?

If so, we’d love to be able to create a win-win scenario for both parties. If you do know someone who might be a fit to work with us and you send us their contact information at (407) 421-9653 before June 24, you’ll be entered to win a $300 gift card. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Movie+Night+Reminder.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Movie+Night+Reminder.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you haven’t gotten tickets to movie night yet, make sure you do soon. If you know someone who is thinking about selling their home, you might also be able to win $300.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you haven’t gotten tickets to movie night yet, make sure you do soon. If you know someone who is thinking about selling their home, you might also be able to win $300.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Time is Best When it is Shared</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/time-is-best-when-it-is-shared.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-05 11:44:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Time is best when it is shared

  
    
  
  
    Have you even noticed that when you see an enormous moon on the horizon that it just isn’t enough to look at it?&nbsp; You have to make sure that at least one other person has looked at it with you.&nbsp; It is almost as if the moon itself isn’t beautiful until the experience of seeing it is shared.&nbsp;&nbsp;
    Derek and I have been traveling with our exchange students (Lotta from Finland and Michi from Sardinia Italy) in our attempt to share as much of America with them that we can.&nbsp; In April we were able to take both of them, along with our friends Patricia and Ron, to Washington DC.&nbsp; Patricia went to Law School in the DC area and she was so happy to be our tour guide through the city.&nbsp; We went to the Ford Theater, toured the Library of Congress, the Capitol building and the monuments around the mall.&nbsp;&nbsp;
  


Patricia was even able to arrange for us to get a tour of the White House.  Unfortunately a man in a wheelchair on Pennsylvania Avenue set himself on fire as we were entering the house.  This triggered another man with a machine gun to ask us to leave.  We decided to comply to the request of the man with the machine gun because it just isn’t smart to argue with a man with a machine gun.  We were all pretty disappointed but Patricia came to the rescue by making some phone calls and getting us tickets to the White House Garden Party that was happening that Sunday.  Now that was lovely!  DC itself is really beautiful in the spring.  The cherry trees are amazing along with everything else that was blooming at the same time.  I had flown through DC years ago but I had never seen it through Derek’s eyes or the eyes of the students. They saw things that I would have never noticed or paid attention to and my experience of the city was really unforgettable because of the wonderful people I shared it with. 

A few years ago I was able to help a couple sell their home in the Sanford area so that they could build a new home near Ashville.  The entire transaction happened over the phone since they were already out of state when the sale happened.  We had kept in touch over the years and once they got the new home completed they asked if I would bring Derek and Lotta up to meet them and stay at the new house.  We worked out the details and after a quick flight we managed to find each other at the Ashville airport because we didn’t know what each other looked like.  

The house they had built is absolutely amazing.  It sits on the side of a hill overlooking a lake surrounded by trees.  The views are beautiful and my favorite area of the house was a screened room overlooking the water.  There are chairs in the room that you could tell were their favorite chairs to sit in and enjoy a morning cappuccino.  They insisted that we sit in their favorite chairs.  You could tell that they truly wanted to see what they had built through our eyes.  That this beautiful setting wasn’t complete until it has been shared with others.   I am so honored that we got to spend that weekend with them because what the two of them have created on that hillside is amazing and I hope that we will be able to share a long friendship.

By the time this letter gets mailed out Lotta will be back home in Finland and Michi will be doing his last Rotary trip before heading back to Sardinia.  I can’t describe how much my heart aches just writing this but I hope they know how much I have enjoyed seeing how beautiful our little corner or the world is through their eyes. 

Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you even noticed that when you see an enormous moon on the horizon that it just isn’t enough to look at it?  You have to make sure that at least one other person has looked at it with you.  It is almost as if the moon itself isn’t beautiful until the experience of seeing it is shared.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you even noticed that when you see an enormous moon on the horizon that it just isn’t enough to look at it?  You have to make sure that at least one other person has looked at it with you.  It is almost as if the moon itself isn’t beautiful until the experience of seeing it is shared.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Speaking to the Founder of the Widowers Support Network</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/speaking-to-the-founder-of-the-widowers-support-network.html</link>
        
          <category>Widowers' Support</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-22 14:15:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Widowers+Support+Network+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Herb Knoll explains to us how his organization, the Widowers Support Network, helps men in need.

There are 2.7 million widowers in America, and 420,000 men become widowers each year. One in every five men will be widowed, and the suicide rate among widowers is three to four times higher than that of married men. 

These are just a few reasons why Herb Knoll began the Widowers Support Network (WSN). It’s his goal to help the millions of widowers across the world overcome the challenges they face each day. Herb joined me today to talk with us more about his organization.

For your convenience, I’ve included timestamps for today’s conversation. Feel free to navigate to the section(s) you’re interested in viewing:

00:05 — Introduction to Herb and the WSN01:11 — Why Herb started the WSN04:06 — What does this network do for people?07:49 — Why being alone with your thoughts can be difficult09:11 — An example of how WSN helped someone12:20 — How to reach out to Herb or get a copy of his book14:50 — Why groups like this are important16:50 — There’s an emotional side to selling property18:00 — A tip from Herb about home equity lines of credit

I’d like to thank Herb for talking with us today. If you’d like to learn more about the Widowers Support Network, visit their website: www.widowerssupportnetwork.com. 

If you have any questions for me about real estate, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Widowers+Support+Network+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Widowers+Support+Network+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Herb Knoll explains to us how his organization, the Widowers Support Network, helps men in need.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Herb Knoll explains to us how his organization, the Widowers Support Network, helps men in need.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Q&A With Local Insurance Expert James Cleveland</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-qa-with-local-insurance-expert-james-cleveland.html</link>
        
          <category>Local</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-26 11:38:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Insurance+Interview.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’ve got questions about insurance, today’s guest can answer them for you. We covered a few of them already in our most recent interview.

I recently had the privilege to interview James Cleveland from Insurance Services of Central Florida to discuss his role in the insurance industry, along with a few related questions. 

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure: 

00:34 - Why did James decide to get started in insurance?

01:18 - What kind of insurance does James and his company specialize in?

03:20 - What is the No. 1 question people ask James about insurance, and what is the answer to that question?

06:00 - What’s the biggest issue James’ customers run into, and what can they do to solve it?

08:20 - What interesting stories has James encountered in his business, and what can we learn from them?

11:18 - How you can get in touch with James for a free policy review (and enter his company’s raffle for a $100 Visa gift card) 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. And if you’d like to learn more about Insurance Services of Central Florida’s gift card raffle, click here.

We look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Insurance+Interview.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Insurance+Interview.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’ve got questions about insurance, today’s guest can answer them for you. We covered a few of them already in our most recent interview.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’ve got questions about insurance, today’s guest can answer them for you. We covered a few of them already in our most recent interview.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Additional Costs to Budget for When Buying a Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/additional-costs-to-budget-for-when-buying-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-11 13:36:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+buying+budget.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are hidden costs to buying a home that you need to be aware of as a homebuyer.

When purchasing a home, there are several costs you need to budget for aside from the price of the home itself.

First is the home inspection fee. In this area, a home inspection typically costs between $300 and $500, depending on the size of the home. You’ll also have to deal with other specialized inspections, such as a termite inspection, which costs anywhere from $75 to $150. 

Next, you’ll need to bring additional cash for the closing costs outside of your lender fees (if you’re paying with financing). These costs include your appraisal fee, which is usually around $450, and insurance fees. Oftentimes, lenders require that you pay a year’s worth of home insurance up front, which can cost anywhere from $1,200 to $3,200. 

After that, you may have to fund an escrow account, since it’s a requirement of many lenders. Funding an escrow account simply means you put money aside into an account that allows your lender to pay your annual taxes and insurance fees. Most lenders prefer that you have three months’ worth of reserves for this.

“Oftentimes, lenders require that you pay a year’s worth of home insurance up front.”

Lastly, there are moving costs to consider. If you have to hire a moving company, for instance, you’ll need to know in advance what you’ll have to pay. We know plenty of movers who charge fair rates and have an impeccable service record that we’d love to refer you to. 

If you have any other questions about this or any other real estate topic, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+buying+budget.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+buying+budget.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are hidden costs to buying a home that you need to be aware of as a homebuyer.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are hidden costs to buying a home that you need to be aware of as a homebuyer.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Tell Whether a Property Is a Good Investment</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-tell-whether-a-property-is-a-good-investment.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-22 12:12:40 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B8-24%5D+_+Investing+in+Real+Estate.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you thinking about investing in real estate? Here are the things you should be looking for.

If you’re thinking about investing in real estate, here are four things to consider that will help you determine whether a property is right for you:

1. Monthly income. What will you get each month from the home?

2. Expenses. Coupled with the monthly income, these make up your ROI. You’ll want to know the cost of your monthly mortgage, including the taxes and insurance. If you’re purchasing a condo or in an HOA, you’ll also want to know about the pertinent fees.

3. The property’s current condition. To give an example, it can easily cost $5,000 to $7,000 to replace an air conditioning system here in Florida. Roofs can be even more expensive. Check to make sure the systems in the home are working properly.

“The expenses and income make up your ROI.”

4. The current tenant situation. If the property already has tenants, have they paid each month on time? How long is the lease? Can you raise the rent, or is it at a good level already? These are all questions you’ll need to answer.

These are just a handful of tips I wanted to share with you today. If you have any other questions about buying or selling real estate in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B8-24%5D+_+Investing+in+Real+Estate.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B8-24%5D+_+Investing+in+Real+Estate.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you thinking about investing in real estate? Here are the things you should be looking for.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you thinking about investing in real estate? Here are the things you should be looking for.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Taking a Moment Not To Think</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/taking-a-moment-not-to-think.html</link>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-02 10:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Taking a Moment Not To Think

Derek and I took our current exchange student, Lotta, to Epcot a few weeks ago to explore the countries of The World Showcase.  We stopped in the China pavilion to watch the 360 movie called Reflections of China. There were a few minute before the movie was going to start so we sat down in the waiting area outside of the theater.  The seating is arranged with long flat benches so I just laid across an entire bench and decided to take a little nap.  Lotta looked at me laying across an entire bench and said “I think it would be great to travel around the world and take naps in different countries.”  I have decided that I love everyone from Finland.

I have had or have witnessed some of the best naps at Disney.  I remember years ago when we took my cousin Aaron and his family to the Magic Kingdom, and we had been there the whole day.  We sat down at 10:30pm on the edge of the Electric Light Parade route and my cousin literally laid his head down on the pavement and fell asleep in a crowd of thousands of people.  Derek wanted to wake him up because he was concerned about not knowing where the pavement had been but I just let him sleep.  I know the wonders of a 10 minute nap and I wouldn’t dream of taking that away from anyone.  

One of my best naps also happened at the Magic Kingdom.  We had taken our friends David and Tiffany and their twin boys into the park for the kid’s first trip to Disney.  We managed somehow to get right to the edge of the parade route for the 3 O’clock Parade and the kids jumped out of their double stroller and ran around while we were waiting for it to come down Main Street.  The stroller was one of those Schwinn runner strollers.  I looked it over and decided, well, the kids weren’t using it at the moment so I climbed in, pulled the top cover over me and went to sleep.   I was later told that the parade reached us and one of the 7 dwarfs walked up to the stroller, pushed the top back slightly, extended his arms toward the stroller to direct everyone’s attention to the man child sleeping in it, ran to get his other 6 dwarf friends to show them the spectacle which then meant the entire crowd was now looking at me napping in the stroller.  Snow White eventually came by and pushed them along with only a slight look of judgment on her face.  I missed the whole thing but I have got to tell you, it was a great nap.   

I think naps are wonderful.  It is just so unfortunate that the only time you really get to have them is when you are a kid.  Do you remember when you were in preschool and they would bring out a mat for nap time and when you woke up you got milk and cookies?   I’m pretty sure that is the description of nirvana.

  
    What I enjoy the most about a nap is that when I let myself detach from the day, even if it is only for a few minutes, I feel like I get a second fresh start.&nbsp; It is as if a moment of no thought opens up the space for new thoughts to come through.&nbsp; I can’t tell you how many times I have been looking at an issue for hours and been stuck as to how to make everyone happy.&nbsp; Then I take a nap or go to a relaxing yoga class, I stop thinking for a moment, and I come back with the new idea that moves the issue forward.&nbsp; There is some true magic in those moments of silence.
    Now if I could just figure out how to get someone to bring me some milk and cookies.&nbsp;
  
  
    
  


Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Derek and I took our current exchange student, Lotta, to Epcot a few weeks ago to explore the countries of The World Showcase.  We stopped in the China pavilion to watch the 360 movie called Reflections of China. There were a few minute before the movie was going to start so we sat down in the waiting area outside of the theater.  The seating is arranged with long flat benches so I just laid across an entire bench and decided to take a little nap.  Lotta looked at me laying across an entire bench and said “I think it would be great to travel around the world and take naps in different countries.”  I have decided that I love everyone from Finland.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Derek and I took our current exchange student, Lotta, to Epcot a few weeks ago to explore the countries of The World Showcase.  We stopped in the China pavilion to watch the 360 movie called Reflections of China. There were a few minute before the movie was going to start so we sat down in the waiting area outside of the theater.  The seating is arranged with long flat benches so I just laid across an entire bench and decided to take a little nap.  Lotta looked at me laying across an entire bench and said “I think it would be great to travel around the world and take naps in different countries.”  I have decided that I love everyone from Finland.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>If Any of These 4 Signs Ring True for You, Think About Downsizing</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/if-any-of-these-4-signs-ring-true-for-you-think-about-downsizing.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-01 11:04:08 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B7-24%5D+_+Downsizing.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If any of the four signs covered in today’s message are true to your homeowner situation, you ought to consider downsizing.

For many, the natural progression of homeownership means eventually upsizing into a larger home. However, certain factors may indicate that simplifying and moving into a smaller home is actually the better option. Here are four of those indicators: 

1. Retirement. All that free time in retirement allows for frequent traveling, and retirees want to have the freedom to do so when they want. Therefore, having a turnkey property is probably more in line with a retired person’s needs.

“The expenses you’re paying on unused space is money that could be directed toward something more worthwhile, like a vacation.”

2. Too much anxiety. In my conversations with homeowners, I sometimes learn that anxiety is weighing on them. Along with the usual stresses of life, it’s not uncommon for these folks to tell me that keeping up with the house, yard maintenance, and other household responsibilities factor into that. This is a piece of the puzzle that can be adjusted through purchasing a smaller home. 

3. Unused space. Maybe there’s space in your home that you’re simply not using. Think of all the extra expenses you’re paying on that space: taxes, utilities, and the list goes on. You could be directing that money toward something more worthwhile, like a vacation, for example. 

4. More opportunities and appreciation. There are sometimes windows of opportunity in our market that allow sellers to realize great appreciation on their home. If you’re looking to sell and downsize, acting within this window might be the difference in you realizing those gains tax free.

If any of these points ring true for your homeownership experience, if you have questions about possibly downsizing, or you have any other real estate-related questions, please call or email me today. I look forward to speaking with you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B7-24%5D+_+Downsizing.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%5B7-24%5D+_+Downsizing.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If any of the four signs covered in today’s message are true to your homeowner situation, you ought to consider downsizing.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If any of the four signs covered in today’s message are true to your homeowner situation, you ought to consider downsizing.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can the KW App Make Home Buying Easy for You?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-the-kw-app-make-home-buying-easy-for-you2.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-22 13:44:12 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+KW+App+Christi.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The KW app can be your best friend if you’re a homebuyer. Here’s why.

Today we just wanted to talk to you a little bit about the Keller Williams app and why you should download it on your phone today.

First of all, it’s going to give you access to us very quickly, as well as real-time property information directly from the MLS.

It’s also your only access to Keller Mortgage, which was founded to give you the opportunity to buy a home with no lender fees.

Take the time now to download the app here, and text or email me a screenshot of the app. If you do, you’ll have the opportunity to win $100. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+KW+App+Christi.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+KW+App+Christi.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The KW app can be your best friend if you’re a homebuyer. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The KW app can be your best friend if you’re a homebuyer. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can the KW App Make Home Buying Easy for You?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-the-kw-app-make-home-buying-easy-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-22 13:44:12 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/Jan+2+-+Mark.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The KW app can be your best friend if you’re a homebuyer. Here’s why.

Today we just wanted to talk to you a little bit about the Keller Williams app and why you should download it on your phone today.

First of all, it’s going to give you access to us very quickly, as well as real-time property information directly from the MLS.

It’s also your only access to Keller Mortgage, which was founded to give you the opportunity to buy a home with no lender fees.

Take the time now to download the app here, and text or email me a screenshot of the app. If you do, you’ll have the opportunity to win $100. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/Jan+2+-+Mark.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/Jan+2+-+Mark.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The KW app can be your best friend if you’re a homebuyer. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The KW app can be your best friend if you’re a homebuyer. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Will You Join Us for Our 2019 Bowling Extravaganza?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/will-you-join-us-for-our-2019-bowling-extravaganza.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-17 16:29:35 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+bowling+event.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our Bowling Extravaganza is right around the corner and you won’t want to miss it.

Happy New Year! We’re sending you this message today to remind you of our upcoming client appreciation event: the 2019 Bowling Extravaganza.

This awesome event will take place on Saturday, February 2 from 11 a.m. to 3 p.m. at Aloma Bowl in Winter Park.

There will be food, fun, prizes, and, of course, bowling! We’re so excited to see all of you there.

To learn all the details and to reserve your spot, visit the event page here. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+bowling+event.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2019/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+bowling+event.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our Bowling Extravaganza is right around the corner and you won’t want to miss it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our Bowling Extravaganza is right around the corner and you won’t want to miss it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is the Home You’re Looking At a Good Deal?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/is-the-home-youre-looking-at-a-good-deal.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-06 11:09:42 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B6-24%255D+%257C+Is+a+Home+a+Good+Deal%253F.mp4</guid>
        <description>

During your home search, there are four main indicators that will help you determine whether a listing is a good deal. We’ll be discussing each of these signs today.

When it comes time to purchase a property, how can you be sure that the home you’re looking at is a good deal? There are actually a few specific indicators, and we’ll be covering four of the best signs today:

1. Price. How much a home costs obviously has a lot to do with whether it’s a good deal. Partnering with a quality agent and a professional lender will help you discern what kind of price is fair and what you should expect to pay for the kind of home you want. 

2. Home features. During your search, you should have a list of features that you’re looking for. Having this list in mind will help you determine how well a given property meets your wants and needs. Better still, have your agent perform a comparative market analysis, during which they will compare a given home against other similar properties in order to assess its value.

“A home’s condition is a crucial component all buyers must consider.”

3. Location. While you can change certain features of a home, you cannot change its location. You should always consider the ways in which a home’s location will impact your life while you live there before making the decision to purchase it.

4. Condition. Buying a home that is move-in ready is something many people prefer, but others still would rather put in the work to customize and fix up whatever home they buy. In either case, make a decision at the beginning of your home search about what you’re looking for. A home’s condition is a crucial component all buyers must consider. 

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B6-24%255D+%257C+Is+a+Home+a+Good+Deal%253F.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B6-24%255D+%257C+Is+a+Home+a+Good+Deal%253F.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>During your home search, there are four main indicators that will help you determine whether a listing is a good deal. We’ll be discussing each of these signs today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>During your home search, there are four main indicators that will help you determine whether a listing is a good deal. We’ll be discussing each of these signs today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Gift</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-gift.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-12 10:12:06 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>The Gift  

Earlier this year Derek and I were approved to host another foreign exchange student through the Rotary Youth Exchange program.  I have to be honest with you that we were both a little nervous after our last experience, but we really believe in the program and the positive effect it has on both the students and for the two of us.  

Our student’s name is Michele (Michi) and he is from the Italian island of Sardinia.  He had a few rough days when he first got here getting use to Dr. Phillips High School and its 3800 students.  Back in Sardinia he had a classroom with 24 other students who stayed in the same room each day.  The teachers rotated per period.  As each teacher came into the room to teach a subject, Michi and his classmates would stand up to greet them.  You can imagine how that went here in Florida on his first day of school.  It didn’t take him long though to adapt.  He is incredibly smart, kind and funny and before we knew it he had made great friends, joined the swim team and was excelling in his classes. 

About a month ago the regional exchange program coordinator and I scheduled a meeting with the Dr. Phillips High school teacher who is in charge of the foreign studies magnet program so that we could discuss how our two programs could support each other.  I asked Michi and Lotta (the other exchange student at Dr. Phillips High School) if they would join us for the meeting during their lunch break.  When we got to the classroom the teacher asked us to come into her closet where she has a little desk and chairs.  I texted Michi the room number and told him that we were in the closet.  Unfortunately Michi and Lotta went to the room above us and when they walked into the classroom, Michi asked the teacher if Mark Ramey was there.  She asked him who Mark Ramey was and Michi told her that I am his host father and that he thought I was in the closet.  She told him that no one was there, but he came back and said “no really, I think he is in the closet.”  Needless to say they eventually found us in the room below and I am still laughing about the whole closet thing. 

Michi will stay with us until the end of December and then he will be staying with another host family from my Rotary Club for the remainder of the school year.  Lotta will be moving from her current host family to stay with us starting in January.  In a sort of weird way it is the limited amount of time with each student that makes this program so amazing.  You see, when you have a student who is learning English and they ask you what though means, you take the time to figure out how to explain what though means.  You question your own language because what does though actually mean? But not just that, when you have a student who will only go to homecoming once in their life, you do everything you can to make it special.  When you have a student that will only have an American Thanksgiving dinner once, you do everything you can to make it special.  It is the sharing of what it means to be an American that makes being an American so special. 


  
    The true gift of the Rotary Youth Exchange program is that even though our time together is limited, each day that we spend with Michi, Lotta and the rest of the exchange students and their host families are extraordinarily special.&nbsp; This is exactly how each day should be, spent as if it is the only special day you have with the people who make you smile the most.&nbsp;
  
  
    
  


Happy Holidays – Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Earlier this year Derek and I were approved to host another foreign exchange student through the Rotary Youth Exchange program.  I have to be honest with you that we were both a little nervous after our last experience, but we really believe in the program and the positive effect it has on both the students and for the two of us.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Earlier this year Derek and I were approved to host another foreign exchange student through the Rotary Youth Exchange program.  I have to be honest with you that we were both a little nervous after our last experience, but we really believe in the program and the positive effect it has on both the students and for the two of us.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Making a Winning Bid in a Seller’s Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-making-a-winning-bid-in-a-sellers-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-15 16:20:37 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B5-24%255D+%257C+Tips+for+Winning+a+Bid+in+a+Seller%2527s+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are four tips you need to follow to make a winning bid in a seller’s market.

If you want to make sure you make a winning bid for the home you want in our seller’s market, here are the four tips you need to follow. 

First, put down a large earnest money deposit. This deposit is money that will actually be yours once the property closes. Many sellers will look at your ability to put down a large deposit as a security blanket, and it will give them confidence in moving forward with your offer. 

Second, show sellers that you’re qualified. Make sure you’re pre-approved before you make an offer. That way, your agent can represent your offer as if it was a cash offer. If you are making an all-cash offer, make sure you have proof of funds. We want to be able to show how strong your offer is when we present it to the seller. 

Next, give sellers time to move. Or, give them their closing date if it fits your schedule. Sometimes sellers feel pressured, and an offer that gives them time to move can be just what you need to give yourself an edge over the competition.

“We want to be able to show how strong your offer is when we present it to the seller.”

Lastly, write your best offer (i.e., your highest and best offer). If you make an offer that’s $3,000 or $5,000 below your ceiling and the buyer selects another bid, how would you feel about that? Would you go back and add that amount to your offer so you get the house you want? If so, state that in your contract. 

If you have any more questions about purchasing a property in a seller’s market or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B5-24%255D+%257C+Tips+for+Winning+a+Bid+in+a+Seller%2527s+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B5-24%255D+%257C+Tips+for+Winning+a+Bid+in+a+Seller%2527s+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are four tips you need to follow to make a winning bid in a seller’s market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are four tips you need to follow to make a winning bid in a seller’s market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating a Hometown Taste With Anthony’s Coal Fired Pizza</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/creating-a-hometown-taste-with-anthonys-coal-fired-pizza.html</link>
        
          <category>Local</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-13 15:19:52 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Interview+With+Debra+Garcia.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The pizzeria’s regional manager, Debra Garcia, shares with us the highlights of her business.

Anthony’s Coal Fired Pizza has brought plenty of delicious food into my life, so of course I needed to learn more about this restaurant. I interviewed the regional manager of the pizzeria chain, Debra Garcia, to learn more about what their great business brings to our area.

To help you navigate to the part(s) you would like to see, I’ve provided timestamps of each topic we discuss.

(00:28) What Debra Garcia does.

(01:16) Why the chain was started.

(02:25) Questions that customers ask (or should ask).

(03:20) Who their customers are.

(04:13) What’s on the menu other than pizza?

(07:39) Interesting customer stories.

(09:48) Restaurant locations and how to contact Anthony’s.

“Anthony’s Coal Fired Pizza has brought plenty of delicious food into my life.”

Visit their website at ACFP.com where you can see menus, locations, and more.

What’s more: they’ve given everybody who reads this a chance to get a free pizza simply by signing up for their reward program here.

If you have any real estate questions or need information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Interview+With+Debra+Garcia.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Interview+With+Debra+Garcia.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The pizzeria’s regional manager, Debra Garcia, shares with us the highlights of her business.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The pizzeria’s regional manager, Debra Garcia, shares with us the highlights of her business.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Expect When Listing Over the Holiday Season</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-to-expect-when-listing-over-the-holiday-season.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-02 13:56:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B15-24%255D+%257C+Selling+During+the+Holidays.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Listing over the holidays can be very effective if you have a good reason to do so, and there are seven key reasons why this is the case.

Many people wonder whether it makes sense to list over the holiday season. Actually, if you have a good reason for listing your property at this time of year, there are a number of different benefits you can enjoy by selling during the holidays. 

1. Buyers are more serious. Those still on the market for a home at this time of year will tend to be very motivated in their search. 

2. There will be fewer homes on the market. For sellers, lower inventory equates to less competition and to more money in their pocket at the end of a deal. 

3. Inventory rises after the holidays. The opportunity to capture increased demand over the holidays won’t last forever. Sellers looking to list at this time of year will need to make their move soon to avoid facing the hot competition of the spring market.

“No one wants to be without a home for the holidays.”

4. Homes show better during the holidays. There’s something about this time of year that evokes a wonderful warm feeling. This can work in the favors who hope to make their listings feel like a home to interested buyers. 

5. Buyers are more emotional during the holidays. No one wants to be without a home for the holidays. Therefore, buyers still on the market at this point of the year may allow this emotional factor to play a role in their decision to purchase your home. 

6. We can restrict showings. Because we realize the holidays are a busy time, our team would be happy to restrict showings of your property so that you can still enjoy the season while your home is on the market. 

7. Selling in the holidays sets you up for success before the new year. If your New Year’s resolution is to get your property sold, listing over the holidays is the perfect way to meet that goal ahead of time.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B15-24%255D+%257C+Selling+During+the+Holidays.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B15-24%255D+%257C+Selling+During+the+Holidays.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Listing over the holidays can be very effective if you have a good reason to do so, and there are seven key reasons why this is the case.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Listing over the holidays can be very effective if you have a good reason to do so, and there are seven key reasons why this is the case.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Questions Should Your Agent Answer Before You Hire Them?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-questions-should-your-agent-answer-before-you-hire-them.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-19 10:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+questions+to+ask+your+agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Don’t just hire the first agent you talk to and have them sell your home. Ask them these questions first.

When you’re making a decision on who the right agent is to help you sell your home, here are a few questions that you should be asking to make sure:

1. How long have you been in the industry? This gives insight into the level of experience that an agent has.

2. What is your track record? How long does it take them, on average, to sell a property?

“A good agent should have a great track record.”

3. How many homes have you sold in the last six to 12 months?

4. What’s your list-to-sale price ratio? This number will give you an idea as to how much money you’ll actually receive when selling your home.

5. Do you have enough staff to support my needs? With the support of my team, I’m able to be out in the field working with buyers and sellers every day to get the results. Agents who don’t have a team of professionals often don’t have the time, resources, and experience necessary to bring you results in the timeline you’re looking for.

6. Do you have a preferred vendor list? This includes vendors who can provide you a high level of service that the agent has already vetted.

Hopefully these tips will make the process of choosing your agent much easier. I would love to apply for the job. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+questions+to+ask+your+agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+questions+to+ask+your+agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Don’t just hire the first agent you talk to and have them sell your home. Ask them these questions first.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Don’t just hire the first agent you talk to and have them sell your home. Ask them these questions first.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips to Make Living in Your For Sale Home Easier</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tips-to-make-living-in-your-for-sale-home-easier.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-05 11:27:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-How+to+Live+in+Your+for+Sale+Home+10.9.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Preparing your home for sale properly is key to getting top dollar. Here are a few expert tips to get you there more quickly.

Your home has always been your sanctuary and your own personal space. When a for sale sign hits the yard, however, agents and buyers are going to want to come through and take a closer look at the property. Here are a few ways to make sure your home is prepared for showings at all times:

1. Start packing now. Remove any and all clutter that you can live without so that the home shows more cleanly and there is plenty of space.

2. Store it, sell it, chuck it, or donate it. Get a storage space and put those things that you can live without in there. Sell, donate, or just throw other items out that you won’t need in your new home to make more space in your current home. The mind records things subconsciously and the more space you have, the more buyers will react positively to that space.

“A squeaky-clean house can bring thousands more in your final sale price.”

3. Get the house squeaky clean. Aim for five-star hotel cleanliness when getting your home ready. A squeaky-clean house can bring $5,000 to $10,000 more when selling. Aim for the stars.

4. Maintain your privacy and safety. Make sure the agent you hire is using an electronically-monitored lockbox. This helps us know who is coming and going when your house is being shown. Also, make sure to put away any valuable belongings during showings.

5. Involve your kids in the process. Make a game of them cleaning up their toys and their room. Make it a contest and offer the winner a prize, which you will get when your home is cleaner and sells for more money.

Moving is never easy, but hopefully these tips make the process much easier for you. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-How+to+Live+in+Your+for+Sale+Home+10.9.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-How+to+Live+in+Your+for+Sale+Home+10.9.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Preparing your home for sale properly is key to getting top dollar. Here are a few expert tips to get you there more quickly.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Preparing your home for sale properly is key to getting top dollar. Here are a few expert tips to get you there more quickly.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do the Most Recent Market Numbers Mean for Your Goals?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-do-the-most-recent-market-numbers-mean-for-your-goals.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-19 11:04:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our third quarter market update for 2018 is here, so let’s examine how recent real estate developments may impact your goals.

Our third quarter market review for 2018 holds good news for homeowners.

Right now, inventory is at a seven- to 10-year low. There were 9,794 homes on the market last month, and, of those, 3,510 sold. This tells us that about 36% of the available homes in our market are selling each month, leaving us with a 2.8-month level of supply. 

Given that a six-month supply is required for a balanced market, our current inventory levels put sellers in the driver’s seat. 

In fact, listings are spending an average of just 46 days on market, and are selling for 90% of asking price. 

However, while rising inventory is good for homeowners, current conditions have created a challenge for today’s buyers. Our own team is currently working with five great families who are searching for the right property to call their next home. 

With this in mind, we have an important question for you: Who do you know who could benefit from selling their home? If anyone comes to mind, please connect them with us.

“While rising inventory is good for homeowners, current conditions have created a challenge for today’s buyers.”

As always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our third-quarter market update for 2018 is here, so let’s examine how recent real estate developments may impact your goals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our third-quarter market update for 2018 is here, so let’s examine how recent real estate developments may impact your goals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are You Protecting Yourself From Deed Fraud?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-protecting-yourself-from-deed-fraud.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-23 16:25:37 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Property+Fraud.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Orange County Comptroller Phil Diamond recently taught me all about deed fraud, and I think you need to know as well.

I recently had the opportunity to hear Phil Diamond of the Orange County Comptroller Office. During his talk, he brought up an important subject: deed fraud. 

Until recently, I didn’t realize how serious this type of fraud is. For those of you who may not know, deed fraud is when someone records fraudulent documents on your property without your knowledge. This fraud can come in the form of a recorded mortgage, lien, or even an unauthorized contractor’s notice of commencement 

What can you do to protect yourself from these things? A good place to start is visiting this website and registering your property so that anytime someone records something on it, you get an email. This will allow you to investigate whether it is legitimate.

“Deed fraud is when someone records fraudulent documents on your property without you knowing.”

Another thing you can do is to frequently check the comptroller office’s records and make sure everything is up-to-date. If your home happens to be unoccupied, you should also be checking the home often to make sure it has stayed that way. It isn’t unheard of for someone to show up and start living in a vacant home. Some may even try to rent it out.

Another good thing to do if you are going away for an extended period of time is to forward your mail. Give your correct mailing address to the Orange County Comptroller Office and the tax deed service so that important things like tax bills aren’t altered. If for some reason you don’t get your trim notice each year, it is a good indication that someone has altered your records. 

If deed fraud does happen to you, the first thing you need to do is report it to the sheriff’s office. Then, you need to report it to the Orange County Comptroller Office as well. 

If you have any questions about this, please feel free to reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Property+Fraud.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Property+Fraud.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Orange County Comptroller, Phil Diamond, recently taught me all about deed fraud, and I think you need to know as well.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Orange County Comptroller, Phil Diamond, recently taught me all about deed fraud, and I think you need to know as well.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Valuable New Resource For You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-valuable-new-resource-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-22 13:11:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+YouTube+Trailer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report

I’d like to welcome you to my new video blog.

On my blog, you’ll find tips for both buyers and sellers in the real estate market, as well as updates on what’s happening in our local market. The real estate market affects all of us!

I really want this page to be a valuable resource for you. If you have any questions about our market or about real estate in general, send me an email. Odds are good that if you have a question about a topic, someone else does as well; so, send your questions my way and we’ll make an educational video.

Take a look around. I look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+YouTube+Trailer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+YouTube+Trailer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What you can do</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-can-do.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-08 11:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>What you can do

The summer heat has forced Derek to a very limited amount of time in our garden so like any enthusiast he has turned to gardening shows on Netflix.  His favorite show at the moment is called Love Your Garden. It is a British show where a crew of professional gardeners surprise a family that is experiencing overwhelming hardships with a complete garden (back yard) makeover.  

The show is hosted by a master gardener named Alan Titchmarsh.  As part of the show he talks with the family members who are living through some pretty rough situations.  In the episode that I watched with Derek he was interviewing a wife who was caring for her husband who had been diagnosed 2 years prior with a condition similar to MS.  In 24 months he had gone from a completely functional person to a wheelchair bound husband who is paralyzed and communicates through a computer.  The wife in the show is a nurse so Alan asked her if she knew his prognosis.  She replied that she couldn’t think about the future, she could only make that day the best day that she could.  Then Alan said something that really struck me.  He said that he didn’t know what to say, but he knew what he could do.  He is a gardener, and he built them a garden. 

The more I get involved with Rotary and our community the more I understand how many people around us are living through difficult times.  I was recently told that per capita, Orlando has the highest number of homeless people of any city in the country.  Many of them have jobs but cannot afford the basic necessities of shelter and food.  I hear stories and I truly don’t know what to say and for a long time I didn’t know what I could do.  Then one day I was talking to a friend of mine from Rotary named Nina and she told me about the organization that she works for called Untied Against Poverty.  

United Against Poverty is an organization that serves those in poverty by providing crisis care, case management, transformative education, food and household subsidy, employment training and placement, personal empowerment training and active referrals to other collaborative social service providers.  They believe that poverty is not permanent, and that people are not defined by their current circumstances.  Best of all they focus on giving individuals and families a hand up, not a hand out.  They understand that no one person or organization can change another person’s difficult experience.  But they can help that person or family get through the day as best as they can and instill the idea that tomorrow will be better.  The magic is that when a person believes that tomorrow will be better, it almost always is. 

Nina has told me stories of individuals that have come off the street to their center on Michigan Avenue and within 12 weeks have completed their programs, been placed in full time employment and are continuing to save money to cover deposits and get a home for themselves and their families. Knowing that I can contribute my time and resources to an organization that’s sole purpose is to inspire and empower people living in poverty to lift themselves and their families to economic sufficiency has allowed me to be confident in what I can do to help our community.  


  
    I am not a gardener, but I know that with a little effort I can help a lot of people have the best day they can, and plant the seeds for an even better day tomorrow. For more information about United Against Poverty you can visit their website at uporlando.org.&nbsp;
  
  
    
  


Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The summer heat has forced Derek to a very limited amount of time in our garden so like any enthusiast he has turned to gardening shows on Netflix.  His favorite show at the moment is called Love Your Garden. It is a British show where a crew of professional gardeners surprise a family that is experiencing overwhelming hardships with a complete garden (back yard) makeover.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The summer heat has forced Derek to a very limited amount of time in our garden so like any enthusiast he has turned to gardening shows on Netflix.  His favorite show at the moment is called Love Your Garden. It is a British show where a crew of professional gardeners surprise a family that is experiencing overwhelming hardships with a complete garden (back yard) makeover.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>“Seasons of Love”</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/seasons-of-love.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-06-05 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>“Seasons of Love”

Derek and I recently went to see the 20th anniversary production of Rent at the Dr. Phillips Performing Arts Center.  It was a great production that brought back a lot of great memories.  The first day I met Derek 20 years ago I was wearing a Rent T shirt.  He asked me if I had seen the show and I asked him if he wanted to go and see it with me.  This was a pretty lame line to try and get his phone number (the show wasn’t playing in Florida, I had seen it in Chicago before I had moved) but it worked, I got his phone number and we have seen the show a few times in the last 2 decades.  

The musical was written and composed by Jonathan David Larson (February 4, 1960 – January 25, 1996).  He was an American composer and playwright noted for exploring the social issues of multiculturalism, addiction, and homophobia in his work.  

I did a little research on Jonathan and to my surprise it turns out that the show Rent is actually quite autobiographical.  He was born in White Plains, New York into a Jewish family.  He participated from an early age in the performing arts including band, choir and drama class.  As a young adult he moved into a 5th story loft in lower Manhattan with no heat and a variety of roommates.  He worked as a waiter for 10 years on the weekends at the Moondance Diner.  If you are familiar with the play, these are all scenes from the show and a lot of the people that he lived with and worked with became the characters and original cast of the musical.  

Jonathan died unexpectedly the morning of Rent’s first preview performance Off Broadway. He suffered an aortic dissection, believed to have been caused by an undiagnosed Marfan syndrome, in the early morning on January 25, 1996.  He was 35 years old. He never saw the show performed in front of an audience.  

To my surprise, I found out the next day that at the same time I was watching Rent on stage, more than a dozen Marjory Douglas High School drama students were performing “Seasons of Love”, the iconic theme song from Rent, at the Tony Awards.  The students were accompanying their drama teacher, Melody Herzfeld, who had just received the 2018 Excellence in Theatre Education Award from the Tony Awards and Carnegie Mellon University. Herzfeld saved 65 lives by barricading her students into a small classroom closet on Valentine’s Day when a former student went on a shooting rampage, killing 17 people and wounding 17 others.

I have to be honest that I was moved to tears when I watched the video of the students singing on stage.  “It’s time now to sing out because the story never ends,” the students sang as the audience wiped their tears and cheered. “Let’s celebrate, remember … the life of friends. It’s about love.”  


  
    I think that Jonathan would be proud to know that even though we still have our struggles, the best way to measure a life is still to measure it in love.&nbsp;
  
  
    
  


Sincerely,

Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Derek and I recently went to see the 20th anniversary production of Rent at the Dr. Phillips Performing Arts Center.  It was a great production that brought back a lot of great memories.  The first day I met Derek 20 years ago I was wearing a Rent T shirt.  He asked me if I had seen the show and I asked him if he wanted to go and see it with me.  This was a pretty lame line to try and get his phone number (the show wasn’t playing in Florida, I had seen it in Chicago before I had moved) but it worked, I got his phone number and we have seen the show a few times in the last 2 decades.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Derek and I recently went to see the 20th anniversary production of Rent at the Dr. Phillips Performing Arts Center.  It was a great production that brought back a lot of great memories.  The first day I met Derek 20 years ago I was wearing a Rent T shirt.  He asked me if I had seen the show and I asked him if he wanted to go and see it with me.  This was a pretty lame line to try and get his phone number (the show wasn’t playing in Florida, I had seen it in Chicago before I had moved) but it worked, I got his phone number and we have seen the show a few times in the last 2 decades.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Luke</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/luke.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-04-04 11:09:17 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>I have noticed over the years that people have a lot in common, and that by sharing our stories we can sometimes help each other get through difficult times because we can see ourselves, and each other, in the story. 

In 1976, I was nine years old when my mother passed away from cancer.  Not long after that I saw the first Star Wars movie, A New Hope, and I couldn’t believe my eyes.  There was this character, Luke Skywalker, and he had lost his family too.  But Luke didn’t cry, he found the force and he used it to bring order to his life.  I decided that if Luke could do it, so could Mark.  I remember sitting at red lights in the back of my stepmother’s car, waving my hand and saying “the light will turn green”.  Guess what, eventually it always did! 

Jumping forward to 2006.  Derek and I got two of the most beautiful Siamese cats in the world.  The kittens were brother and sister from the same litter, and I insisted that we call the boy cat Luke Skywalker.  I wanted to call his sister Leia, but Derek was adamant that he was not going to be sitting in the vet’s office when they called out for Luke Skywalker and Princess Leia to come back to the examining room. We settled on the name Tabitha for Luke’s sister.  

I was right though about Luke, he was a Jedi.  He would look at me with his blue eyes and wherever I was, thinking about something in the past or worrying about something in the future, he would use the force to bring me back to the present.  Somehow he would know that I was back and he would put his forehead to my forehead as if to say “stay here, this is where life is”.  He was a very wise cat and one of my most beloved companions. 

After 12 years, Luke’s health took a turn for the worse.  We did everything that we could, but his kidneys failed and he stopped eating.  As many of you have had to do with your own pets, we made the decision to stop his suffering.  I thought that I would be a wreck, but when he stopped breathing I was actually overwhelmed with a sense of peace.  He was out of pain and in some way, he was free.

Believing that I had the power to change traffic lights brought order to my chaotic childhood.  Believing that Luke is somehow still a part of me, even if that belief is childish, brings me peace at this present moment, which is exactly where he would want me to be.  Mark Ramey

Luke Skywalker - 2006 to 2018
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I have noticed over the years that people have a lot in common, and that by sharing our stories we can sometimes help each other get through difficult times because we can see ourselves, and each other, in the story.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I have noticed over the years that people have a lot in common, and that by sharing our stories we can sometimes help each other get through difficult times because we can see ourselves, and each other, in the story.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Johnny</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/johnny.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-01-01 10:19:18 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Last year Derek and I decided that we would like to participate as host parents to a student through the Rotary Youth Exchange program.   We filled out all of the applications, took all of the tests, passed all of the background checks and happily qualified to be part of the program.  Our student arrived from Poland at the beginning of August.  His name was Janek (Johnny), and he was an absolutely incredible 16 year old kid.  

Johnny had traveled through most of Europe, but had never been to the United States.  He had some strong pre-conceived notions about Florida.  When he first arrived I took him down to a lake near my house to go paddle boarding, and every time the water rippled he screamed alligator!  We ended that trip pretty fast.  The walk from our house to the bus stop is a few blocks.  It is really dark in the morning so we got Johnny a little flashlight that just happened to have a laser pointer attached to it.  He loved the laser pointer because he was convinced that if he saw an alligator on the way to the bus stop he could use the laser to distract it while he escaped.  He had practiced running our cat Lucky into the wall with a laser pointer a bunch of times so why wouldn’t it work with an alligator.

He also had a list of things he wanted to try that he considered distinctly American.  These included things like hamburgers, macaroni and cheese, Taco Bell, Wendy’s, Mountain Dew and outlet stores. What he didn’t expect, and what we were so proud of, was how he embraced the extraordinarily diverse student population at Dr. Phillips High School.  He seemed to make friends with everyone instantaneously.    

The Rotary Exchange Program has some pretty specific rules that the student must follow or they get sent back home.  Without getting into the details, because the details aren’t important, Derek came home from work one day and found evidence that one of the rules had been broken. He waited for me to get home, and we made the call together to the regional program coordinator.  Johnny was headed back to Poland a few days later.  I think we cried for at least 2 days. 

There is an article in the February 2018 edition of The Rotarian Magazine where the magazine is interviewing a fellow Rotarian named Mary Ann Peters.  She is the CEO of The (Jimmy) Carter Center.  The Carter Center is known for waging peace with the world.  In the article Mary Ann talks about the importance of the Rotary Youth Exchange Program.  “She recalls meeting a Muslim leader in Bangladesh who told her that he could never be anti-American because he had been on an exchange program and lived with a family in Pennsylvania.”

When people ask Derek and I if we would participate in the program again we always answer yes, for a couple of reasons. First, even though our experience with Johnny didn’t go the way we thought it would, the integrity of the program has made a lasting impression on his life in a very positive way.  We have communicated with him and his parents since he got back home to Poland.  He is in a new school and he has fallen in love with a beautiful girl. Best of all, he is making very good choices.  


  
    The second reason we say yes is because you never know, as Mary Anne Peters can attest, how sharing your life for just a few months can change what someone from another country knows to be true about America.&nbsp;&nbsp;
  
  
    
  


Mark Ramey 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Last year Derek and I decided that we would like to participate as host parents to a student through the Rotary Youth Exchange program.   We filled out all of the applications, took all of the tests, passed all of the background checks and happily qualified to be part of the program.  Our student arrived from Poland at the beginning of August.  His name was Janek (Johnny), and he was an absolutely incredible 16 year old kid.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Last year Derek and I decided that we would like to participate as host parents to a student through the Rotary Youth Exchange program.   We filled out all of the applications, took all of the tests, passed all of the background checks and happily qualified to be part of the program.  Our student arrived from Poland at the beginning of August.  His name was Janek (Johnny), and he was an absolutely incredible 16 year old kid.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Crying Together</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/crying-together.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2017-11-11 09:47:15 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Crying Together

Let me start by saying that this isn’t a sad letter, it is actually the opposite.  One of Derek’s co-workers recently invited us to participate with her family in the Autism Speaks 5k Walk in Altamonte Springs.  The Autism Speaks organization hosts several 5K walks in Florida each year to help raise funds and to increase the understanding and acceptance of people with autism spectrum disorder. 

Derek’s co-worker’s name is Kathy and she has 3 grandchildren that all exhibit traits within the spectrum of autism.  Autism Speaks defines autism this way;  autism, or autism spectrum disorder, refers to a range of conditions characterized by challenges with social skills, repetitive behaviors, speech and nonverbal communication, as well as by unique strengths and differences. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) estimates autism’s prevalence as 1 in 68 children in the United States. This includes 1 in 42 boys and 1 in 189 girls.

We met Kathy, her two daughters and her grandchildren at Cranes Roost Park.  I asked the mothers what their experience has been like to raise children with autism.  They told me that the hardest part is getting schools and teachers to accommodate their children’s needs.  Each child with autism is different, and they react differently to situations.  The 5K event itself used pompoms in the opening ceremony as a sensory neutral way for the audience to cheer without making noise.  I never thought clapping could negatively affect a child with autism.  This is that kind of information that Autism Speaks is trying to get people to understand. 

So, without a gun shot, the walk began just as rain clouds rolled over the area.  Even with umbrellas we all got pretty soaked on the first lap around the lake.  By the second lap about 90% of the participants had abandoned the walk, but Kathy isn’t the kind of person that lets a little rain stop her or her family.  So at different paces we started the 3rd lap in the pouring rain.  The kids were having a blast splashing in puddles and running in circles when the youngest grandson suddenly took off running.  His oldest sister tried to catch up with him but couldn’t.  He disappeared and all of us panicked.  What seemed to be an eternity later we heard the commentator announce that they had a lost boy at the main stage. It was him and he was safe. 

I was with Kathy when she and her family found her youngest grandson.  They were all pretty shook up but his oldest sister, who couldn’t catch up to him, was crying uncontrollably.   Kathy held her daughters, and they held their children and they cried together.  Autism can deny a person the capacity to control their emotions.  So Kathy met the kids where they were, engulfed in the raw experience of loss, fear, and guilt.  Even though everything was fine, she didn’t tell them how to feel, she joined them and they cried together as a family.  

We have emotions for a reason.  I truly believe that I saw this family heal by just letting them out and not reacting the way they should, but by the only way they could.  My new understanding of autism has me thinking that the rest of us should give that “letting them out” thing a try.  It feels great! 


  
    If you would like to get more information about Autism Speaks, check out their web site at autismspeaks.org and if you feel inclined to do so, donations are always welcome.&nbsp;
  
  
    
  


Happy Holidays – Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Crying Together

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Crying Together

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Saving the Raccoons</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/saving-the-raccoons.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2017-09-09 11:00:32 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Saving the Raccoons

May I first say that I hope you are all well and that the hurricanes have not disrupted your lives. I don’t know how that would be possible because hurricanes, by nature, are disruptive but I hope that you and your families are well.

Derek and I took a shower at the gym on Tuesday after the storm and headed back to work.  When we got back home that night our power was back on. He told me that he had been helping to re-open the office building that he works at the whole day.  This included walking around the building and picking up all the garbage (and random car parts) that had blown around during the storm.  When he got to the dumpsters to throw the trash away, he opened the side access panel and saw a face staring back at him.  It was a raccoon that had ridden out the storm in the dumpster.   Derek then turned around and looked into a second dumpster.  There was another terrified raccoon sitting on a box surrounded by 8 inches of murky water. 

Now Derek knows better than to reach into a dumpster to try and pull out a raccoon.  Any animal that is that afraid is going to bite you, regardless of your intentions.  So Derek walked over to one of the maintenance managers and asked him if he had access to any wood that they could prop into the dumpster to make ramps.  Miraculously, he just happened to have 4 perfect pieces of wood in the back of his truck.  They took each piece and propped them into the dumpster so that the raccoons could climb out.  They stood back, but nothing happened. They gave them an hour and still nothing, the raccoons were too scared to move.  In the end, pest control was called, and two men in proper gear arrived and pulled the raccoons out with grabbers.  They were released later that day in a nature reserve.

On the Saturday before the storm Derek had a different experience.  When he arrived at work to help secure the building for the rapidly approaching hurricane, he heard that there had been a young woman causing trouble in the lobby.  Apparently she had shown up that morning with a large duffle bag that seemed to contain everything she owned and had sat down in the building’s lobby like she was setting up a camp to ride out the storm.  Different people who work in the building approached her to see if she needed some help. but she was quite belligerent to each of them.  Eventually the manager on duty was called in.  When she approached the young woman with the duffle bag, there was quite the exchange of words.  In the end the woman took her bag, walked outside and sat on a bench in the 95 degree sun.  Eventually she took the bag and walked away.

Now we instinctively know that an animal in fear will bite us, and yet we will go to great lengths to make sure that they get to safety.  When did we forget that people can also lash out from fear?  On reflection, Derek just wished that he could have said “I know that this is scary, I can help you get to a shelter where you will be safe” and that she would have been able to hear him and accept the help.  

We don’t always know what to do. We don’t always know where to go, and we all experience fear.  It is our ability to see past it, to help the person lashing out at us and to accept help from people who care about us that makes us human.  Maybe our lives need a little disruption to remind us that without compassion, we are all alone standing on a box in murky water.  

Sincerely,

Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>May I first say that I hope you are all well and that the hurricanes have not disrupted your lives. I don’t know how that would be possible because hurricanes, by nature, are disruptive but I hope that you and your families are well.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>May I first say that I hope you are all well and that the hurricanes have not disrupted your lives. I don’t know how that would be possible because hurricanes, by nature, are disruptive but I hope that you and your families are well.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Alaskan Lupin</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-alaskan-lupin.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-31 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>The Alaskan Lupin

Many of you read the last letter that I sent out in regards to a trip that I took earlier this summer through Scandinavia. I have one more story that I would like to share with you about the cruise that I think you will enjoy.  After leaving the picturesque port of Alesund, Norway the ship headed northwest into the Arctic Circle.  The sun never went down, it just slid across the horizon and after a day and night at sea the ship approached Akueyri, Iceland.  

Tourism is a rather new phenomenon in many parts of Iceland.  Akueyri is a port town on the northwest corner of the island that is surrounded by natural wonders. These include thermally active fields, similar to Yellowstone Park in Wyoming, lava formations and a gorgeous waterfall with a river of glacial water.  When we arrived, I would guess that the residents had never seen a ship like the Disney Magic.  The middle school summer band greeted us at the dock with a unique mix of Michael Jackson hits.  It was the cutest thing that we had ever seen. 

When we got off the ship and onto a tour bus we were greeted by our guide. She was actually a local teacher that was off for the summer.  She was admittedly the worst tour guide ever (she didn’t actually tell us her name until over an hour into the trip) but we all loved her.  She tried to teach us how to say the alphabet and how to sing Happy Birthday in Islandic.  It was like having Rose from the Golden Girls narrate a day of her life with a bus microphone.  It was her sincerity that truly pulled us all in.  She just wanted us to enjoy where she lived, to see the beauty that she sees in the land that is her home.  

Throughout the day as we drove by massive fields of purple flowers, our guide told us that they were Alaskan Lupin.  They were imported into Iceland from North America to try and keep what little topsoil the Island has from blowing away (most of Iceland is covered in old lava fields).  Alaskan Lupin is a hardy flowering plant that can survive in harshly cold environments.   She went on to tell us that the only problem with the flower is that it doesn’t understand anything about borders, it has spread everywhere.  The flowers are doing exactly what they were intended to do, except that they have absolutely changed the entire landscape of the island. 

Our dear friend Mary was sitting with us on the tour and she reflected that she had moved to Orlando in 1951.  Tourism wasn’t new at the time, people had been traveling to the Silver Springs State Park in Florida to ride the glass bottom boats since 1878, but it had its borders.  The borders of tourism in Orlando are long gone, along with the orange groves that are now walled neighborhoods and strip malls. You could almost see the pain in her eyes as she thought about what tourism will do to this little island.  Yet there we were, Iceland tourists, enjoying the fields of non-indigenous purple flowers and the wondrous sights that the island has to offer.


  
    It is an interesting moment when you realize that you are the tourist leaving your footprint on someone else’s land.&nbsp; Being from Orlando, the shoe is usually on the other foot.&nbsp; Tourism changes the landscape. That is inevitable and what it was intended to do. It is the people who sincerely share the essence of what makes their home special with others that truly makes the world a beautiful place to visit. &nbsp; Being that person is what makes Orlando so special for the rest of the world.&nbsp;
  
  
  
  


Sincerely,

Mark Ramey 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Many of you read the last letter that I sent out in regards to a trip that I took earlier this summer through Scandinavia. I have one more story that I would like to share with you about the cruise that I think you will enjoy.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Many of you read the last letter that I sent out in regards to a trip that I took earlier this summer through Scandinavia. I have one more story that I would like to share with you about the cruise that I think you will enjoy.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inspired to Climb</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/inspired-to-climb.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2017-07-02 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Inspired to Climb

About 3 years ago, Derek noticed that the Disney Magic Cruise Ship did a summer trip through Scandinavia that looked incredible.  As soon as he showed it to me, we both agreed that we would have to do this trip as soon as possible.  Possible didn’t come that soon. But after saving up some vacation funds and coordinating a lot of schedules with our friends Mary, Carol, Alinda and Ricky, we all just recently flew from Orlando to London.  A transfer took us to the port and we boarded the Disney Magic that was docked under the White Cliffs of Dover, England!

The ship’s itinerary would take us up the coast of Norway, through the Arctic Circle, around Iceland, south to Scotland and back to Dover, with stops along the way.  As we were planning the excursions in advance of sailing, Alinda and Ricky immediately signed up for a 5 hour hike of “Preikestolen”, also known as Pulpit Rock just outside of Stavanger, Norway.  The pictures and description of the excursion looked incredible, the pinnacle of the hike is a sheer cliff that is 1982 feet above the Lysefjorden. Derek and I had considered doing the climb ourselves but had chosen against it because neither of us wanted to risk getting hurt on day 2 of the cruise. 

What surprised us about Alinda and Ricky signing up for the hike is that Alinda was diagnosed with Parkinson’s disease about 2 years ago and Ricky has a very stiff ankle from a previous skiing injury so it just didn’t seem like something they would enjoy.  When we called Alinda to make sure that she had signed up for the correct excursion, she told us that she had noticed that since her diagnosis she had chosen to not move around much.  She would stay seated at her job as much as possible because it was when she moved that she would experience the tremor effects of Parkinson’s.   She had since made the decision that she was tired of being Alinda who has Parkinson’s, she was going to be Alinda who has Parkinson’s**and climbs mountains and Ricky was going to be right by her side, stiff ankle and all. 

After talking to Alinda, Derek and I were inspired to be fearless mountain climbers ourselves so we also signed up for the excursion and started training about 3 months before we left for the trip. Derek joined Jenny Craig and lost 20 pounds while he worked with his trainer Jason at the gym, and I trained on my bike along with some friends from Rotary.  It took some work, but when we got to the base of Pulpit Rock, we were ready to take the risk and climb the mountain.  

The weather was perfect, the trail was treacherous, and the view at the top was awe inspiring.  Alinda and Ricky made it half way up and back. She is actually still recovering from the tremendous effort that she committed to the hike and she had to spend the rest of the vacation in a wheelchair.  Does she regret it?  Alinda who has Parkinson’sandclimbs mountains regrets nothing, and I couldn’t be more proud.


  
  Life throws mountains at us, whether they are in the form of a diagnosis or actual mountains.&nbsp; We get to choose if we want to take the risk to actually experience the climb exactly as we are, instead of sitting on the sidelines wishing that we were the kind of person that gets to the top.&nbsp;
  
  
     
  


We really are what we call ourselves, 

Mark Ramey

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>About 3 years ago, Derek noticed that the Disney Magic Cruise Ship did a summer trip through Scandinavia that looked incredible.  As soon as he showed it to me, we both agreed that we would have to do this trip as soon as possible.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>About 3 years ago, Derek noticed that the Disney Magic Cruise Ship did a summer trip through Scandinavia that looked incredible.  As soon as he showed it to me, we both agreed that we would have to do this trip as soon as possible.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Perfect Odd Couple</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-perfect-odd-couple.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-06 10:41:01 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>The Perfect Odd Couple

One of my favorite times of the day is when I get home in the evening and Derek and I get to tell each other stories from our day.  Derek is a licensed massage therapist and he works several days a week at a local time share resort.  He works in a pool side cabana where resort guests can come directly from the pool to massage table.  He has a lot of fun with the job and he is never lacking in great stories.  He told me this story the other night and I thought you might like it.

Derek was taking a lunch break when he received a text that he had a 3:00 appointment with Bob at the cabana.  He headed back from his break to set up for the appointment when he saw two people standing in front of the cabana, one wearing dark glasses and holding the shoulders of the other person.  As he approached them the man in front introduced himself as Adam and he explained that Bob was standing behind him and he was blind.

Now this is how Derek described Adam, if you saw him in a dark alley, you would probably walk the other way. Adam was about 30 years old but his face was badly wrinkled from a lifetime of smoking, he was covered in tattoos (including permanent tear drops down his cheeks) and he didn’t have any teeth.  It seemed to Derek that life had not been easy for Adam, but even with that said he did help complete Bob’s paperwork and helped get him situated on the massage table before heading over to the lake to go jet skiing for the first time.  

From the table Bob explained to Derek that he had a hereditary degenerative disease that had taken his eyesight about 10 years earlier and was continuing to shut down other parts of his body as well.  Derek described him as a thin layer of skin over a skeleton.  There wasn’t much of him left but he got massages whenever he could because human touch was one of the only things left that gave him comfort.  When Derek asked him if the rest of his family was traveling with him, Bob explained that he owned a very large bussing company up in Massachusetts and that the rest of his family wasn’t able to travel with him any longer because they were running the company.  He couldn’t stand the thought of not using his time shares so even though he preferred the company of his wife, he enjoyed traveling with his employee Adam.  

At the end of the massage, Adam came back from the lake with the biggest smile you can have without any teeth and helped Derek get Bob off the table and into a chair. While the two of them walked over to the cashier, Adam told Derek that Bob’s family refused to travel with him because he was too much trouble, but that Bob had always taken care of Adam and that he would always take care of Bob.  Adam told Derek that he had been to places all over the country with Bob and seen and done things that he had never thought possible. 

When the two of them got back to the cabana, Adam stood in position so that Bob could put his hands on his shoulders to be lead back to their vacation villa.   As he was leaving Bob told Derek that he had worked his whole life to get everything he thought he wanted, at the expense of everything he had, including his health, and in the end it turned out that all he really needed was a friend. 

It is amazing to me how clearly a blind man can see.

Sincerely, 

Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>One of my favorite times of the day is when I get home in the evening and Derek and I get to tell each other stories from our day.  Derek is a licensed massage therapist and he works several days a week at a local time share resort.  He works in a pool side cabana where resort guests can come directly from the pool to massage table.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>One of my favorite times of the day is when I get home in the evening and Derek and I get to tell each other stories from our day.  Derek is a licensed massage therapist and he works several days a week at a local time share resort.  He works in a pool side cabana where resort guests can come directly from the pool to massage table.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating the Conditions</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/creating-the-conditions.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-04 10:57:17 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Creating the Conditions

My partner Derek was first introduced to hummingbirds when he traveled up to Michigan to help my father after he was diagnosed with lymphatic cancer.  At the time, my father had decided to go through his chemotherapy treatments in Florida, but he and my stepmother needed help getting their house in Michigan closed up, so Derek flew up to help them get everything ready and eventually drove them both to Orlando.  Now, Derek had seen hummingbirds before but never in the numbers that there are in Michigan.  He was enamored with them at once and has been ever since. 

Several years went by after my father passed and one day Derek was watering a tree that he had planted in our yard and a hummingbird did a cork screw spin around the stream of water coming from the hose.  Derek couldn’t believe his eyes. He had never seen a hummingbird in Florida but there it was, right in front of him.  He immediately called our dear friend Eileen, who has the most beautiful butterfly gardens, and asked her if she had seen hummingbirds in Florida before and she told him that she has them in her garden all of the time.  Derek was elated and Eileen agreed to meet him at Lucas Nursery in Oviedo to buy some plants that attract hummingbirds and butterflies to your garden.  

When Derek and Eileen arrived at Lucas Nursery, Derek was overwhelmed with the selection of plants that they offered!  Luckily Eileen had a lot of experience and she guided him to purchase two specific varieties, the Mexican Firecracker bush (also called the dwarf hummingbird bush) and the salmon colored porter weed along with other blooming plants.  Each one is an excellent nectar plant that hummingbirds love.  Eileen explained to Derek that attracting hummingbirds is really the same as attracting butterflies, you just have to create the conditions in your yard that they enjoy and let them find you.  

I came home from work and Derek had drawn up an entire garden lay out with irrigation lines, pots, planters, borders and everything else between.  I just looked at him and said, “Good thing your parents are coming for the spring!”  One of the things that I admire about Derek is that he isn’t afraid to dream big because if he can draw it, his parents can build it.  Nothing makes me happier than watching the three of them creating something beautiful out of nothing, together.  I, of-course, pitch in whenever I can, but even if I am at work, I just can’t wait to get home to see what they have created.  I so appreciate all of them for making my life so beautiful. 

The first garden was completed about 4 years ago and the new plants filled in almost immediately and that first summer the hummingbirds found us.  A red throated male and a brown female.   They came back the next summer, to even larger gardens, and then two years ago, 2 babies arrived.  They were so small that at first we thought they were dragon flies but we recognized the flight pattern from the parents and eventually we were able to get close enough to confirm that they were baby hummingbirds.  Last year another two babies joined the family and as I am writing this the shrubs are about to bloom so we should be seeing all of them again soon this summer. 


  
  Don’t be afraid to create the conditions in your life that inspire you this spring.&nbsp; Take your ideas, write them down, draw them out, talk to your friends and family members and get started.&nbsp; Let people help you and enjoy the process of creating the possibility of something beautiful simply finding you.
  
  
     
  


Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My partner Derek was first introduced to hummingbirds when he traveled up to Michigan to help my father after he was diagnosed with lymphatic cancer.  At the time, my father had decided to go through his chemotherapy treatments in Florida, but he and my stepmother needed help getting their house in Michigan closed up, so Derek flew up to help them get everything ready and eventually drove them both to Orlando.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My partner Derek was first introduced to hummingbirds when he traveled up to Michigan to help my father after he was diagnosed with lymphatic cancer.  At the time, my father had decided to go through his chemotherapy treatments in Florida, but he and my stepmother needed help getting their house in Michigan closed up, so Derek flew up to help them get everything ready and eventually drove them both to Orlando.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Being a Piece of the Solution</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/being-a-piece-of-the-solution.html</link>
        
          <category>Letters of the Heart</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2017-02-02 09:44:04 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Being a Piece of the Solution

One of the biggest reasons that I really enjoy being a member of the Rotary Club of Dr. Phillips is how the group has introduced me to so many wonderful things that are happening in our community and how I can actually participate with organizations that are truly benefitting not just our own neighborhoods but also the world.  Recently the Rotary Club of Dr. Phillips partnered with the Rotary Club of Lake Buena Vista to work with an organization called Rise Against Hunger to bag 10,000 meals to ship to Haiti which was reeling from the devastation of Hurricane Matthew.  

Prior to volunteering to work on this project I had never heard of Rise Against Hunger so I decided to do a little research on the organization.  Rise Against Hunger was formed in 1998 and to date has partnered with local communities and organizations to package and distribute over 3 million meal packages (each one able to feed 6 people) to 74 different countries.  According to their statistics just under 800 million people in the world don’t get the food they need to live a healthy life.  66 million primary school aged children across the developing world go to school hungry every day.  

When I read the statistics I felt a little sick to my stomach.  I write a list of things that I am grateful for every morning and I have to admit that I have never added “food” to the list.  I just never really thought about it in a manner of having or not having food.  Growing up, my German Grandparents were of the mindset that the more you eat the better you are.  This of course had something to do with me weighing 111 pounds in 3rd grade and having to wear husky jeans.  So yes, the question of “what” was for lunch had been a part of my life, but I have thankfully never experienced “is” their lunch. Obviously my experience is not everyone’s experience and for the first time I truly understood the need to help people that don’t have enough food.  But there I was, one person, what could one person do?

This is the beauty of the Rotary Club, you are never alone.  When Rise Against Hunger approached the Rotary Club of Lake Buena Vista in regards to the hungry people in Haiti they immediately contacted our club so that we could combine our resources to be able to purchase the food that we would be packaging.  Then we let our combined members do what they do best.  One of them located space in a convention center to process the food.  They asked me to be in charge of collecting volunteers, which wasn’t hard at all.  We needed 50 volunteers and we stopped asking when our list exceeded 65.  We were ready to package some food!

On project day, the Rise Against Hunger team had the entire processing area organized and ready to go.  As each volunteer signed in they were assigned a simple task.  Some people measured beans, some measured rice.  I personally ran a machine that heat sealed the packages of food so that they were ready to ship.  Together our group of family and friends processed 10,216 meal packages in about 90 minutes.  Our efforts fed over 61,000 people.  


  
  Hunger, like so many of the problems that are happening around us, can seem overwhelming until you realize that you only have to be willing to make the choice to be part, just a piece, of the solution.&nbsp; One person standing next to their friends and family can do amazing things.&nbsp;&nbsp;
  
  
     
  

Mark Ramey 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>One of the biggest reasons that I really enjoy being a member of the Rotary Club of Dr. Phillips is how the group has introduced me to so many wonderful things that are happening in our community and how I can actually participate with organizations that are truly benefitting not just our own neighborhoods but also the world.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>One of the biggest reasons that I really enjoy being a member of the Rotary Club of Dr. Phillips is how the group has introduced me to so many wonderful things that are happening in our community and how I can actually participate with organizations that are truly benefitting not just our own neighborhoods but also the world.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Inspiration</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/inspiration.html</link>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-31 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Inspiration

I am always inspired by the people I meet, and as the New Year begins I like to take a moment to reflect on what it is about people that inspires me the most.  It seems that the quality of Integrity continues to be at the top of the list.  I have had the honor of attending three Eagle Scout award ceremonies that have commemorated the high level of integrity and achievement of three exceptional young men, and I would love to share with you their inspirational stories.  Here is some information about the Eagle Scout program that will give us all some perspective.  

Eagle Scout is the highest achievement or rank attainable in the Boy Scouting program of the Boy Scouts of America (BSA). Only four percent of Boy Scouts are granted this rank after a lengthy review process. Requirements include earning at least 21 merit badges. The Eagle Scout must demonstrate Scout Spirit, an ideal attitude based upon the Scout Oath and Law, service, and leadership. This includes an extensive service project that the Scout plans, organizes, leads, and manages.

The first Eagle Scout award ceremony that I attended was for a young man named Austin Rumbley who was a member of the church youth group that I mentored.  I had always known Austin as a natural leader within the group, and I always knew that I could count on him.  I recently spoke to him about his experience as an Eagle Scout, and he told me that his ability to lead came from accomplishing his final required service project.  He admitted that when he was younger he was not very organized so his troop leader asked him to write down what he wanted to accomplish, to speak the words he had written, and then he held him accountable to accomplishing what he said he would do. Austin learned that your word is everything, without it you have nothing.  Integrity.

Kyle Stanley is the son of two dear clients and friends that I have had the honor to work with.  When I asked Kyle why he decided to complete the Eagle Scout ranking, he told me that it fit perfectly with his quest to better himself and to be part of the change that he wants to see in the world.  He then told me that a good leader looks at the people in front of him and finds out what their best skill is and lets them do what they are good at.  Confidence comes from a positive attitude and knowing that you are capable of more than you think.  Integrity. 

Jephon White is the son of one of my very first clients and friends.  He just recently received his Eagle Scout badge, and when we spoke about his accomplishment, he told me that he originally wanted to complete his final project to make his parents and peers proud of him.  What surprised him the most was how proud he was of himself when he discovered that it is ok to struggle, that everyone struggles, and that working through the struggle is what makes us capable of achieving great things.  Individual determination doesn’t come from someone else, it is discovered in each of us.  Integrity.

I am so proud to know all three of these young men, and I am looking forward to watching them accomplish their goals to be a Law Enforcement Officer, a Navy Seal and an Aerospace Engineer.   As I look forward to 2017 I have decided to write down my goals, to be accountable to do what I say I will do, to lead by allowing others to do what they are good at, and to know that I can be proud of what has been accomplished.  In essence my goal is to live in integrity.  Sometimes I wonder what my life would have been like if I had this mind set when I was 17.   I guess it is never too late to be inspired by an Eagle Scout. 

Mark Ramey
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I am always inspired by the people I meet, and as the New Year begins I like to take a moment to reflect on what it is about people that inspires me the most.  It seems that the quality of Integrity continues to be at the top of the list.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I am always inspired by the people I meet, and as the New Year begins I like to take a moment to reflect on what it is about people that inspires me the most.  It seems that the quality of Integrity continues to be at the top of the list.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Mark Ramey</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Mark Ramey</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Mark Ramey Group - your professional Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
