<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Podcast with Mark Ramey</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Mark Ramey Group - your professional Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Mark Ramey</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-11-30 11:43:55 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Mark Ramey</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Mark@TheMarkRameyGroup.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Mark Ramey</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Dr. Phillips-Windermere Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Mark Ramey Group - your professional Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Tips for Making a Winning Bid in a Seller’s Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/4-tips-for-making-a-winning-bid-in-a-sellers-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-15 16:20:37 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B5-24%255D+%257C+Tips+for+Winning+a+Bid+in+a+Seller%2527s+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

There are four tips you need to follow to make a winning bid in a seller’s market.

If you want to make sure you make a winning bid for the home you want in our seller’s market, here are the four tips you need to follow. 

First, put down a large earnest money deposit. This deposit is money that will actually be yours once the property closes. Many sellers will look at your ability to put down a large deposit as a security blanket, and it will give them confidence in moving forward with your offer. 

Second, show sellers that you’re qualified. Make sure you’re pre-approved before you make an offer. That way, your agent can represent your offer as if it was a cash offer. If you are making an all-cash offer, make sure you have proof of funds. We want to be able to show how strong your offer is when we present it to the seller. 

Next, give sellers time to move. Or, give them their closing date if it fits your schedule. Sometimes sellers feel pressured, and an offer that gives them time to move can be just what you need to give yourself an edge over the competition.

“We want to be able to show how strong your offer is when we present it to the seller.”

Lastly, write your best offer (i.e., your highest and best offer). If you make an offer that’s $3,000 or $5,000 below your ceiling and the buyer selects another bid, how would you feel about that? Would you go back and add that amount to your offer so you get the house you want? If so, state that in your contract. 

If you have any more questions about purchasing a property in a seller’s market or you have any other real estate needs, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B5-24%255D+%257C+Tips+for+Winning+a+Bid+in+a+Seller%2527s+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B5-24%255D+%257C+Tips+for+Winning+a+Bid+in+a+Seller%2527s+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There are four tips you need to follow to make a winning bid in a seller’s market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There are four tips you need to follow to make a winning bid in a seller’s market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating a Hometown Taste With Anthony’s Coal Fired Pizza</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/creating-a-hometown-taste-with-anthonys-coal-fired-pizza.html</link>
        
          <category>Local</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-13 15:19:52 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Interview+With+Debra+Garcia.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The pizzeria’s regional manager, Debra Garcia, shares with us the highlights of her business.

Anthony’s Coal Fired Pizza has brought plenty of delicious food into my life, so of course I needed to learn more about this restaurant. I interviewed the regional manager of the pizzeria chain, Debra Garcia, to learn more about what their great business brings to our area.

To help you navigate to the part(s) you would like to see, I’ve provided timestamps of each topic we discuss.

(00:28) What Debra Garcia does.

(01:16) Why the chain was started.

(02:25) Questions that customers ask (or should ask).

(03:20) Who their customers are.

(04:13) What’s on the menu other than pizza?

(07:39) Interesting customer stories.

(09:48) Restaurant locations and how to contact Anthony’s.

“Anthony’s Coal Fired Pizza has brought plenty of delicious food into my life.”

Visit their website at ACFP.com where you can see menus, locations, and more.

What’s more: they’ve given everybody who reads this a chance to get a free pizza simply by signing up for their reward program here.

If you have any real estate questions or need information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Interview+With+Debra+Garcia.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Interview+With+Debra+Garcia.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The pizzeria’s regional manager, Debra Garcia, shares with us the highlights of her business.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The pizzeria’s regional manager, Debra Garcia, shares with us the highlights of her business.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What to Expect When Listing Over the Holiday Season</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-to-expect-when-listing-over-the-holiday-season.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-02 13:56:58 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B15-24%255D+%257C+Selling+During+the+Holidays.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Listing over the holidays can be very effective if you have a good reason to do so, and there are seven key reasons why this is the case.

Many people wonder whether it makes sense to list over the holiday season. Actually, if you have a good reason for listing your property at this time of year, there are a number of different benefits you can enjoy by selling during the holidays. 

1. Buyers are more serious. Those still on the market for a home at this time of year will tend to be very motivated in their search. 

2. There will be fewer homes on the market. For sellers, lower inventory equates to less competition and to more money in their pocket at the end of a deal. 

3. Inventory rises after the holidays. The opportunity to capture increased demand over the holidays won’t last forever. Sellers looking to list at this time of year will need to make their move soon to avoid facing the hot competition of the spring market.

“No one wants to be without a home for the holidays.”

4. Homes show better during the holidays. There’s something about this time of year that evokes a wonderful warm feeling. This can work in the favors who hope to make their listings feel like a home to interested buyers. 

5. Buyers are more emotional during the holidays. No one wants to be without a home for the holidays. Therefore, buyers still on the market at this point of the year may allow this emotional factor to play a role in their decision to purchase your home. 

6. We can restrict showings. Because we realize the holidays are a busy time, our team would be happy to restrict showings of your property so that you can still enjoy the season while your home is on the market. 

7. Selling in the holidays sets you up for success before the new year. If your New Year’s resolution is to get your property sold, listing over the holidays is the perfect way to meet that goal ahead of time.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B15-24%255D+%257C+Selling+During+the+Holidays.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+%255B15-24%255D+%257C+Selling+During+the+Holidays.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Listing over the holidays can be very effective if you have a good reason to do so, and there are seven key reasons why this is the case.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Listing over the holidays can be very effective if you have a good reason to do so, and there are seven key reasons why this is the case.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Questions Should Your Agent Answer Before You Hire Them?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-questions-should-your-agent-answer-before-you-hire-them.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-19 10:33:37 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+questions+to+ask+your+agent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Don’t just hire the first agent you talk to and have them sell your home. Ask them these questions first.

When you’re making a decision on who the right agent is to help you sell your home, here are a few questions that you should be asking to make sure:

1. How long have you been in the industry? This gives insight into the level of experience that an agent has.

2. What is your track record? How long does it take them, on average, to sell a property?

“A good agent should have a great track record.”

3. How many homes have you sold in the last six to 12 months?

4. What’s your list-to-sale price ratio? This number will give you an idea as to how much money you’ll actually receive when selling your home.

5. Do you have enough staff to support my needs? With the support of my team, I’m able to be out in the field working with buyers and sellers every day to get the results. Agents who don’t have a team of professionals often don’t have the time, resources, and experience necessary to bring you results in the timeline you’re looking for.

6. Do you have a preferred vendor list? This includes vendors who can provide you a high level of service that the agent has already vetted.

Hopefully these tips will make the process of choosing your agent much easier. I would love to apply for the job. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+questions+to+ask+your+agent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+questions+to+ask+your+agent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Don’t just hire the first agent you talk to and have them sell your home. Ask them these questions first.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Don’t just hire the first agent you talk to and have them sell your home. Ask them these questions first.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Tips to Make Living in Your For Sale Home Easier</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-tips-to-make-living-in-your-for-sale-home-easier.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-10-05 11:27:12 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-How+to+Live+in+Your+for+Sale+Home+10.9.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Preparing your home for sale properly is key to getting top dollar. Here are a few expert tips to get you there more quickly.

Your home has always been your sanctuary and your own personal space. When a for sale sign hits the yard, however, agents and buyers are going to want to come through and take a closer look at the property. Here are a few ways to make sure your home is prepared for showings at all times:

1. Start packing now. Remove any and all clutter that you can live without so that the home shows more cleanly and there is plenty of space.

2. Store it, sell it, chuck it, or donate it. Get a storage space and put those things that you can live without in there. Sell, donate, or just throw other items out that you won’t need in your new home to make more space in your current home. The mind records things subconsciously and the more space you have, the more buyers will react positively to that space.

“A squeaky-clean house can bring thousands more in your final sale price.”

3. Get the house squeaky clean. Aim for five-star hotel cleanliness when getting your home ready. A squeaky-clean house can bring $5,000 to $10,000 more when selling. Aim for the stars.

4. Maintain your privacy and safety. Make sure the agent you hire is using an electronically-monitored lockbox. This helps us know who is coming and going when your house is being shown. Also, make sure to put away any valuable belongings during showings.

5. Involve your kids in the process. Make a game of them cleaning up their toys and their room. Make it a contest and offer the winner a prize, which you will get when your home is cleaner and sells for more money.

Moving is never easy, but hopefully these tips make the process much easier for you. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-How+to+Live+in+Your+for+Sale+Home+10.9.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-How+to+Live+in+Your+for+Sale+Home+10.9.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Preparing your home for sale properly is key to getting top dollar. Here are a few expert tips to get you there more quickly.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Preparing your home for sale properly is key to getting top dollar. Here are a few expert tips to get you there more quickly.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Do the Most Recent Market Numbers Mean for Your Goals?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-do-the-most-recent-market-numbers-mean-for-your-goals.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-09-19 11:04:39 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Market+Update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our third quarter market update for 2018 is here, so let’s examine how recent real estate developments may impact your goals.

Our third quarter market review for 2018 holds good news for homeowners.

Right now, inventory is at a seven- to 10-year low. There were 9,794 homes on the market last month, and, of those, 3,510 sold. This tells us that about 36% of the available homes in our market are selling each month, leaving us with a 2.8-month level of supply. 

Given that a six-month supply is required for a balanced market, our current inventory levels put sellers in the driver’s seat. 

In fact, listings are spending an average of just 46 days on market, and are selling for 90% of asking price. 

However, while rising inventory is good for homeowners, current conditions have created a challenge for today’s buyers. Our own team is currently working with five great families who are searching for the right property to call their next home. 

With this in mind, we have an important question for you: Who do you know who could benefit from selling their home? If anyone comes to mind, please connect them with us.

“While rising inventory is good for homeowners, current conditions have created a challenge for today’s buyers.”

As always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Market+Update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Market+Update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Our third-quarter market update for 2018 is here, so let’s examine how recent real estate developments may impact your goals.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Our third-quarter market update for 2018 is here, so let’s examine how recent real estate developments may impact your goals.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Are You Protecting Yourself From Deed Fraud?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/are-you-protecting-yourself-from-deed-fraud.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-23 16:25:37 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Property+Fraud.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Orange County Comptroller Phil Diamond recently taught me all about deed fraud, and I think you need to know as well.

I recently had the opportunity to hear Phil Diamond of the Orange County Comptroller Office. During his talk, he brought up an important subject: deed fraud. 

Until recently, I didn’t realize how serious this type of fraud is. For those of you who may not know, deed fraud is when someone records fraudulent documents on your property without your knowledge. This fraud can come in the form of a recorded mortgage, lien, or even an unauthorized contractor’s notice of commencement 

What can you do to protect yourself from these things? A good place to start is visiting this website and registering your property so that anytime someone records something on it, you get an email. This will allow you to investigate whether it is legitimate.

“Deed fraud is when someone records fraudulent documents on your property without you knowing.”

Another thing you can do is to frequently check the comptroller office’s records and make sure everything is up-to-date. If your home happens to be unoccupied, you should also be checking the home often to make sure it has stayed that way. It isn’t unheard of for someone to show up and start living in a vacant home. Some may even try to rent it out.

Another good thing to do if you are going away for an extended period of time is to forward your mail. Give your correct mailing address to the Orange County Comptroller Office and the tax deed service so that important things like tax bills aren’t altered. If for some reason you don’t get your trim notice each year, it is a good indication that someone has altered your records. 

If deed fraud does happen to you, the first thing you need to do is report it to the sheriff’s office. Then, you need to report it to the Orange County Comptroller Office as well. 

If you have any questions about this, please feel free to reach out to me by phone or email. I look forward to speaking with you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Property+Fraud.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+Property+Fraud.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Orange County Comptroller, Phil Diamond, recently taught me all about deed fraud, and I think you need to know as well.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Orange County Comptroller, Phil Diamond, recently taught me all about deed fraud, and I think you need to know as well.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A Valuable New Resource For You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-valuable-new-resource-for-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Mark Ramey</author>
        <pubDate>2018-08-22 13:11:05 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+YouTube+Trailer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Want to sell your home? Get a FREE home value report

I’d like to welcome you to my new video blog.

On my blog, you’ll find tips for both buyers and sellers in the real estate market, as well as updates on what’s happening in our local market. The real estate market affects all of us!

I really want this page to be a valuable resource for you. If you have any questions about our market or about real estate in general, send me an email. Odds are good that if you have a question about a topic, someone else does as well; so, send your questions my way and we’ll make an educational video.

Take a look around. I look forward to hearing from you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+YouTube+Trailer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Mark+Ramey/2018/The+Mark+Ramey+Group-+YouTube+Trailer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Mark Ramey</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Dr. Phillips-Windermere, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Mark Ramey</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Mark Ramey</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Mark Ramey Group - your professional Dr. Phillips-Windermere Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
